[
  { 
    "id":"f2a1004f-3b7e-4f96-83c6-7374e3df7cb1",
    "question": "As latitude increases; ",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"pressure gradients increase",
    "correctAnswer":"Coriolis force increases",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:46:57.655668",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"pressure gradients decrease",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Coriolis force decreases"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4effa1ab-affb-4f8a-ba44-b12bf3cabc6c",
    "question": "What causes an Emergency Locator Transmitter (ELT) to activate automatically?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Setting the transponder code to 7700.",
    "correctAnswer":"High g-force/rapid deceleration, and in some cases immersion in water.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.6(a)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:42:50.044447",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Setting the ELT remote switch to \"ON\".",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"If any carbon monoxide is detected by the cockpit CO detector."
  },
  { 
    "id":"483974d4-15a2-4628-832c-3755a3c93c76",
    "question": " Night is defined as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the end of morning civil twilight and the end of evening civil twilight",
    "correctAnswer":"the end of evening civil twilight and the beginning of morning civil twilight",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:40:03.010154",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the end of morning civil twilight and the beginning of evening civil twilight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the beginning of morning civil twilight and the end of evening civil twilight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"327cfb49-ee6d-4ed4-a9a2-f475da6ceb14",
    "question": "You're approaching an aerodrome with an inoperative radio. You see a series of red flashes from the light gun, meaning...",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Give way to other aircraft and continue circling",
    "correctAnswer":"Aerodrome unsafe, do not land",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:44:56.610850",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Danger, be on the alert",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Return for landing (clearance to land and taxi will be given in due course)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5853151e-9f97-4a6f-ab20-e40f1082c8b2",
    "question": " In the SADIE decision making model, the D stands for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Decide on who should solve the problem",
    "correctAnswer":"Develop a solution",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:59:28.295839",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Discuss the problem with other crew",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Define the problem to be solved"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bf24417c-8b01-40e1-bad3-7c1a11120176",
    "question": "If you have been diving to a distance of 15 metres, you should not fly for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"6 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"24 hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:59:58.255751",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"12 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"48 hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"31cca24b-9c78-4ddf-a6e2-a3ba329ec1a7",
    "question": "Pursuant to CAR Part 91, the legal minimum fuel reserve on a Cross Country VFR flight by day is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"45 minutes at normal fuel consumption",
    "correctAnswer":"30 minutes at normal fuel consumption",
    "syllabusReference":"6.46.8",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:49:38.940417",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"sufficient fuel for the flight and to get to one suitable aerodrome, plus 15 minutes at normal fuel consumption",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"sufficient fuel for the flight and to get to a suitable alternate aerodrome"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c72cbf6f-c31c-4123-9bd5-ce83429a420e",
    "question": "When flying low in mountainous terrain, not in the vicinity of a repeater station",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"VHF signals are more likely to be received than HF signals because HF signals require line of sight",
    "correctAnswer":"HF signals are more likely to be received than VHF signals because VHF signals require line-of-sight",
    "syllabusReference":"2.2.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 09:31:56.951405",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"you should always adhere to TIBA procedures",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"VHF signals are likely to be received in the lee of a mountain range, relative to the broadcast antenna"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5279a77c-37c2-4809-863d-50610d9cdc4d",
    "question": "You have flown a total of 162 nautical miles and it has taken you 2 hours and 30 minutes. What is your average ground speed?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"68 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"65 knots",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:46:14.415146",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"60 knots",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"108 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5725fc6e-f440-4532-870b-ca1e1a472716",
    "question": "What is one exception that allows a pilot in command of an aircraft operating at an aerodrome not to follow the published circuit pattern?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"They have permission from the Director of CAA",
    "correctAnswer":"They are operating an aircraft at an aviation event",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:57:01.548334",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"During operation at night, in the opinion of the pilot in command the non-published approach provides for better noise abatement",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The non-published approach provides a shorter and more efficient flight path"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0c724784-4b0c-4aaf-a61b-3e06d1dba2fa",
    "question": "When performing a fuel drain check in a light aircraft a small amount of fuel is drained from the tanks and;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"if any water is present in the sample it will show as bubbles at the top of the sample",
    "correctAnswer":"if any water is present in the sample it will show as bubbles at the bottom of the sample",
    "syllabusReference":"12.30.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:36:42.637037",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a reagent, which reacts with water, is used to test for its presence",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"if the tank contains any water, fuel will be unable to be drained from the tank"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b2956ce2-dc33-4efc-bcff-40ff1173b84b",
    "question": "The operator of an aircraft must retain the technical log of an aircraft;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"for at least 24 months after the date of the last entry in the technical log",
    "correctAnswer":"for at least 12 months after the date of the last entry in the technical log",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:36:40.626389",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"until audited by a scheduled CAA review",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"until two further technical logs have been issued for that aircraft"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6db2e3b5-f481-4923-8345-f21099044cd7",
    "question": "If your intended track is 271 degrees True, variation is 22 degrees east, what heading should you steer to maintain track? Assume nil values for any other relevant factors.",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"293 degrees magnetic",
    "correctAnswer":"249 degrees magnetic",
    "syllabusReference":"6.4.10",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:50:16.414287",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"113 degrees magnetic",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"069 degrees magnetic"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5fa53114-c6d3-4fca-833c-f9ba3281f093",
    "question": "In the tropical latitudes, what height are high level clouds?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"15,000 feet and above",
    "correctAnswer":"20,000 feet and above",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:40:07.468318",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"17,000 feet and above",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"13,000 feet and above"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2d862413-d17c-47b3-8f34-99c160eb7da7",
    "question": "At low-levels in the mid latitudes, the saturated adiabatic lapse rate is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1.98℃ per thousand feet gain in height",
    "correctAnswer":"1.5℃ per thousand feet gain in height",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:13:01.025928",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"2℃ per thousand feet gain in height",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"3℃ per thousand feet gain in height"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5bcfd9b4-79e1-4ea2-b0b5-75e9590e831e",
    "question": "If ATC instructs you to \"STOP SQUAWKING ALTITUDE\", what should you do?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Set the transponder mode to \"ALT\" (Mode C).",
    "correctAnswer":"Set the transponder mode to \"ON\" (Mode A).",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.8",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:32:36.419133",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Set the transponder mode to \"ON\" (Mode C).",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Set the transponder mode to \"ALT\" (Mode A)."
  },
  { 
    "id":"f136e4f2-2d47-4635-80fb-cc8b304d3c6b",
    "question": "The standard SI and ICAO units in which distance and temperature are measured are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"miles and Kelvin",
    "correctAnswer":"nautical miles and degrees Celcius",
    "syllabusReference":"12.2.2(a) & (f)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:32:57.397879",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"nautical miles and degrees Kelvin",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"kilometres and degrees Celsius"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2d85fcd2-7f56-42ab-8243-66862e937633",
    "question": "In a constant rate 1 turn, how many degrees per second does an aircraft turn?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"6 degrees per second",
    "correctAnswer":"3 degrees per second",
    "syllabusReference":"12.66.12",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:31:45.617743",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Between 9 and 12 degrees, depending on the speed of the aircraft",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Between 3 and 9 degrees, depending on the weight of the aircraft"
  },
  { 
    "id":"813a3905-c0db-4669-8cd6-053f186e111d",
    "question": "You're on the ground at a towered aerodrome and see a series of green flashes from the tower's light gun, meaning...",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Cleared for take-off",
    "correctAnswer":"Cleared to taxi",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:51:22.708117",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Taxi clear of landing area in use",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Return to starting point on aerodrome"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b07f45d7-2e22-4354-9a9e-9a25a1e6478f",
    "question": "A flight crew operating under CAR Part 135 must not fly in excess of;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"50 hours in any 7 consecutive days",
    "correctAnswer":"160 hours in any 30 consecutive days",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:57:32.605944",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"100 hours in the preceding 28 days",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"1000 hours during the immediate preceeding 365 days"
  },
  { 
    "id":"52b94de1-bdac-4f33-9961-e1e96afd6b12",
    "question": "The transition layer varies in different countries due to considerations about the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"general circulation conditions in each latitude, which affects air pressure",
    "correctAnswer":"Minimum Safe Altitude",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:44:35.629338",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"airspace and traffic saturation, particularly around high use airspace",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"pressure conditions that exist in different latitudes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d46ef261-2bac-480b-a33b-a9a837babd82",
    "question": " When considering a frontal thunderstorm, as a rule, the intensity of these thunderstorms is greatest when;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the front is slow moving and the advancing air is very cold",
    "correctAnswer":"the front is fast moving and the advancing air is very cold",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:30:20.557782",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the front is slow moving and the advancing air is warm",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the front is fast moving and the advancing air is warm"
  },
  { 
    "id":"09071976-0705-4120-9329-39273eb0781a",
    "question": "If you weren't able to understand a radio transmission, what is the correct phrase to request the sender to repeat themselves?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"CORRECTION",
    "correctAnswer":"SAY AGAIN",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(k)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:26:51.978563",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"PLEASE REPEAT",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"MISUNDERSTOOD"
  },
  { 
    "id":"29c5ea6e-d6ab-485e-8243-f900921c9fec",
    "question": "When is it generally recommended to turn on the aircraft radio?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Before engine start to ensure any transmissions from taxiing aircraft can be heard",
    "correctAnswer":"After engine start, to prevent the radio being damaged by voltage spikes during engine start",
    "syllabusReference":"2.4.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 10:04:02.438796",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"As late as possible immediately prior to taxi, to prevent the aircraft battery from being drained",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"As soon as you enter the aircraft"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4a027ddc-e9a4-4166-83fb-29ac1ba04501",
    "question": "A transponder code of 7700 indicates",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an urgency situation, which does not involve immediate danger to those in the air or on the ground",
    "correctAnswer":"an emergency situation, such as an engine failure",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.6",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 10:18:55.477338",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a loss of communications",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a hijacking"
  },
  { 
    "id":"90c61950-dc30-4690-bdb0-f9fe2de899e5",
    "question": "What does the term \"WILCO\" mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"I have received all of your previous transmission.",
    "correctAnswer":"I understand your message and will comply with it.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:40:09.173567",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Will continue with the previous ATC instruction.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"I am unable to comply with your previous transmission."
  },
  { 
    "id":"838a2dc4-b610-438b-b7bf-086a7a84ad48",
    "question": "What is the correct way to transmit the time 11:30pm?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Eleven thirty pee em",
    "correctAnswer":"Two tree tree zero",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(e)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:58:48.421197",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"One one tree zero",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Twenty-three tree zero"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b2170ef3-3c38-4688-92ba-b3cfddc825a4",
    "question": "What is 2160 divided by 90?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"240",
    "correctAnswer":"24",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:58:19.577420",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"42",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"420"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bd27e8da-ecba-49c4-8081-1c5989ee7d83",
    "question": "When the wind on a weather map blows along isobars which are straight it is referred to as which type of wind?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"centripetal",
    "correctAnswer":"geostrophic",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:14:09.395297",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"gradient",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"cyclostrophic"
  },
  { 
    "id":"845b03df-2dd2-4cb1-a845-3db6f1da7b07",
    "question": "  If you file a flight plan and nominate a SARTIME of 0230 UTC, search and rescue action will be initiated at what time?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"0300 UTC",
    "correctAnswer":"0230 UTC",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:35:06.390697",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"0300 NZDT",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"0230 NZST"
  },
  { 
    "id":"96283e23-930d-4a0e-9433-b21aacc9e749",
    "question": "You get airborne out of Paraparaumu aerodrome on the way to Foxpine aerodrome to the north. What is the highest altitude you can fly without entering into controlled airspace?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"4,500 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"2,000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:46:16.272138",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"1,500 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"3,500 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d945997c-10f5-45a6-bc24-f29d4b283730",
    "question": "You are looking at a chart with a given scale of 1:250 000. If the distance on the chart between two places was 8cm, what would the actual distance be across the ground?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"200 km",
    "correctAnswer":"20 km",
    "syllabusReference":"6.22.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:51:31.173972",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"31.25 km",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2000 km"
  },
  { 
    "id":"701483f7-b9bb-403d-ba78-015ecabb0c10",
    "question": "What speed restrictions apply to VFR aircraft?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"They are generally limited 250 knots if below 10,000 feet in any airspace but clearance from an ATS unit can be obtained if a higher speed is desired",
    "correctAnswer":"They are generally limited to 250 knots if below 10,000 feet and in classes C, D and G airspace",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:45:41.335549",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"They are generally limited to 250 knots if below 10,000 feet and in class G airspace only",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"They are generally limited to 250 knots in classes C and D airspace only"
  },
  { 
    "id":"887cda26-d95a-419e-b2d2-cb9623a3a52f",
    "question": "A katabatic wind;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"is a down slope wind that develops from mid morning",
    "correctAnswer":"is a down slope wind that develops from the early evening",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:32:50.088046",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"is an upslope wind that develops from mid morning",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"is a up slope wind that develops from the early evening"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d8281168-5a8e-4a10-8e7a-4547f611a26b",
    "question": " The average height of the tropopause at the poles is approximately;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"52,500 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"29,500 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:12:46.331594",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"60,000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"36 000 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c1adfa1e-db56-4047-bc56-c76ab147c4e6",
    "question": "A licensed commercial pilot does not need to complete a Biennial Flight Review if they;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"maintain a current D category instructor rating",
    "correctAnswer":"meet the agricultural currency requirements prescribed in rule 61.107",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:32:58.988268",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"are flying for a certificated Air Transport Operation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"have remained current on at least one type of aircraft for the full preceding two years"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0d4b3b26-dede-4887-951f-d5b4862e40b8",
    "question": " In the mid latitudes, what height are medium layer clouds?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"7000 feet to 20000 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"7000 feet to 17000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:15:10.624493",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"5000 feet to 17000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"5000 feet to 20000 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"18cf10e7-ba8c-4b8b-8278-99db9363cdbd",
    "question": "An Emergency Locator Transmitter should only be tested;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"during the first 30 minutes of each hour, and for a maximum of three siren sweeps",
    "correctAnswer":"during the first 5 minutes of each hour, and for a maximum of three siren sweeps",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.10",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:31:35.058359",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"during the first 5 minutes of each hour, and for a maximum of 30 seconds",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"during the first 5 minutes of each hour, and for a maximum of 15 seconds"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0885c8b4-f181-4fa4-b6d9-5790b9773e9d",
    "question": "If a person has had their medical certificate revoked, who must they surrender the medical certificate to?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The Director, a licensed aviation medical examiner, or a constable.",
    "correctAnswer":"The Director, a person authorised by the Director, or a constable.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.2.10",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 04:30:34.329482",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"A medical certificate can only be surrendered directly to the Director.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"An A-Cat flight instructor, or licensed medical examiner."
  },
  { 
    "id":"bd554e82-219f-4c5e-9c92-6c58a4f27e6a",
    "question": " Which of the following is an example of a zeitberger?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"A reduced work performance due to fatigue",
    "correctAnswer":"Lunch and dinner",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:03:48.356929",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"An aircraft arriving after its ETA",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Eating a vegetarian meal instead of meat"
  },
  { 
    "id":"216b991f-3d70-425f-9c91-bb56b419bd3c",
    "question": "What is the correct pronunciation of \"4\" in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Four",
    "correctAnswer":"Fow-er",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:17:49.605761",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Floor",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Fort",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(c)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"75f4be12-f323-4f3d-b711-000b95fe9ca5",
    "question": "What must the holder of an aviation license have to do if they have a change in their medical condition that may interfere with the safe exercise of the privileges of their license?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Advise the Director of the change as soon as practicable. They may continue to exercise privileges of their license as long as the Director has been notified.",
    "correctAnswer":"Advise the Director of the change as soon as practicable, and not exercise privileges of the license related to their medical certificate.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.2.8",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 04:24:13.401738",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Advise the Director of the change within 30 days. Not operate aircraft for hire or reward, but can continue to operate aircraft for their personal use without carrying passengers.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Use \"best judgement\" about whether to continue to operate aircraft for personal use, and seek guidance from their personal doctor."
  },
  { 
    "id":"ecaf0b4f-feb0-4ba2-9c82-68c53a1dad9f",
    "question": "The type of cloud most likely to be seen following the passage of a cold front is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"cirrus and cumulonimbus",
    "correctAnswer":"cumulus and cumulonimbus",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:42:00.027423",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"stratus and altostratus",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"nimbostratus and cumulus"
  },
  { 
    "id":"66714543-8084-43c1-ae5f-d8d3c5ead56c",
    "question": "  The diurnal variation of pressure has the most significance in the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"high latitudes",
    "correctAnswer":"low latitudes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:43:48.396291",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"areas where Coriolis force is greatest",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"mid latitudes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6f04e0d8-87f8-4c86-98ed-93ce24cf23af",
    "question": "You take off from Wellington International airport on 2 January 2018 at 8am, and your expected flight time to New Plymouth is 2 hours 23 minutes. What is your ETA at New Plymouth in UTC?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"2 January at 2123 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"1 January at 2123 hours",
    "syllabusReference":"6.16.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:45:34.103553",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"1 January at 1023 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2 January at 1023 hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6f38ea15-74e8-47c1-aff3-e9d9b4cdfb1b",
    "question": " The factors involved in determining the visibility due to slant range are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"distance through the haze or mist layer, airspeed, and wind direction",
    "correctAnswer":"distance through the haze or mist layer, the density of the layer, and height above the ground",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:31:49.627645",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"density of the haze or mist layer, height above the ground, and environmental lapse rate",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"distance through the haze or mist layer, airspeed, and environmental lapse rate"
  },
  { 
    "id":"664237cc-4faf-461e-a2a5-cb80cbe80673",
    "question": "Whilst flying, your aircraft suffers a vacuum system failure.  The instruments that will be affected are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"airspeed indicator and compass",
    "correctAnswer":"artificial horizon and directional indicator",
    "syllabusReference":"12.40.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:38:10.376841",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"vertical speed indicator and airspeed indicator",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"altimeter and directional indicator"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5579a29a-9b3a-4405-a1a0-b883febaec13",
    "question": "Specific factors which influence the decision making process are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"recency, confusion, discrepancies",
    "correctAnswer":"age, experience, belief in relevance",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:08:24.422983",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"culture, checklists, short term memory retention",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"individual differences, risk shift, performance"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ee3b599f-9e84-4e62-8565-f041562827a1",
    "question": " Super cooled water droplets (SCWD) are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"cloud droplets with a temperature of between -20℃ and +3℃",
    "correctAnswer":"cloud droplets with a temperature colder than 0℃",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:45:51.610675",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"super saturated water droplets",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"water droplets cooled by falling through a frontal inversion"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3ed409a6-f082-425a-b6d5-f33341c4075a",
    "question": "The minimum fuel reserve for a VFR flight by night in an aeroplane is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"30 minutes",
    "correctAnswer":"45 minutes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:49:18.992885",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"15 minutes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"one hour"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2aa1bf3f-ea61-4266-9066-3c9aca96d205",
    "question": "An 'air transport operation' means an operation for the carriage of passengers or goods by hire or reward, except for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a helicopter operation",
    "correctAnswer":"agricultural operations",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:36:04.369004",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a freight only operation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a flight training operation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"03508313-a07d-431f-86a8-7693549bd3c2",
    "question": "You're approaching a towered aerodrome and have lost communications. You see a series of alternating red and green flashes from the tower's light gun. What does this mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Give way to other aircraft and continue circling",
    "correctAnswer":"Danger, be on the alert",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:48:17.864620",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Aerodrome unsafe, do not land",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Return for landing (clearance to land and taxi will be given in due course)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ca0ad203-d3bb-4dba-b2aa-a33dd8dab3c9",
    "question": "The amount of heat units (in Joules) required to raise the temperature of a unit mass by 1°C is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"latent heat",
    "correctAnswer":"specific heat",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:48:12.712358",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"sensible heat",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"solar heat"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6ee35f87-8633-438f-bf03-0a096a9d951c",
    "question": " CAR Part 135 provides that single engined aircraft on air operations must not be operated over water for a distance of 10 nm beyond gliding distance, unless a life raft of sufficient size to carry all occupants of the aircraft is carried and;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a multi-engined aircraft is used for the air operation",
    "correctAnswer":"a life preserver is worn by each passenger",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:37:55.632034",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the flight is under radar coverage for the duration of the flight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"one ELT or EPIRB person is carried"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e209bfab-7c92-4b67-9569-b59c6873f446",
    "question": "Factors affecting teamwork are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"diverse culture, fear, rules",
    "correctAnswer":"trust, diverse culture, lack of direction",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:08:49.914069",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"communication, internal conflict, trust",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"zeitbergers, lack of direction, rules"
  },
  { 
    "id":"73bd8c6b-4cf4-4999-9b53-a562d20e8f9d",
    "question": "When are you able to self-test an ELT?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"In the first 5 minutes after the hour, for a maximum of 5 siren sweeps.",
    "correctAnswer":"In the first 5 minutes after the hour, for a maximum of 3 siren sweeps.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.10",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 00:50:57.204228",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"In the last 5 minutes before the hour, for a maximum of 3 siren sweeps.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Any time as long as the ELT is in the ARM position."
  },
  { 
    "id":"61732860-b6cf-4df8-86ad-29dc935200e1",
    "question": "The term \"QNH\" refers to the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"altimeter subscale setting of 1013.2",
    "correctAnswer":"atmospheric pressure from stations, reduced to mean sea level using ISA values",
    "syllabusReference":"6.12.2(i)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:43:02.415911",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"atmospheric pressure from stations, reduced to mean sea level using atmospheric values",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"ambient atmospheric pressure at a given datum"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e369c066-dd56-47f2-b07c-3b2485dd0e51",
    "question": "When is it allowed to omit the \"ZK-\" from a callsign? eg. for ZK-LJF this would be \"Lima-Juliet-Foxtrot\".",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"During high workload times only.",
    "correctAnswer":"When the ground station has used this callsign and it's unlikely to cause confusion with other aircraft.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(i)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:20:33.764343",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"When the controller requests the aircraft use their full callsign.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"When flying under radar control."
  },
  { 
    "id":"3f9a4318-fb2b-4ef6-8b5f-35dd87e81c00",
    "question": "As pilot-in-command, which statement is true about the preflight action required for communication/navigation facilities?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"You must check the status of all communication and navigation facilities within 50NM of your flight path.",
    "correctAnswer":"You must check the status of any communication and navigation facilities intended to be used.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(a)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:21:50.333225",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"You are only required to check the status of a communication facility if no alternative facility exists on your flight path.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"You are only required to check the status of navigation facilities if using VOR navigation."
  },
  { 
    "id":"f222c4dd-5b6c-4a02-8bbe-abf5f2c5be66",
    "question": " 'SARTIME' is the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"time that the search and rescue authorities use to coordinate their respective actions",
    "correctAnswer":"time nominated by a pilot for the initiation of alerting action",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:37:04.086915",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"time at which air traffic services will cease providing any flight following information or action",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"time nominated by the pilot as an estimated time of arrival"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bb83d081-5897-46f4-a6e7-6e43a9a331f2",
    "question": "In New Zealand, Aviation Gasoline (Avgas) is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"straw coloured, and contains no lead",
    "correctAnswer":"coloured blue, and contains some lead",
    "syllabusReference":"12.16.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:35:52.117269",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"coloured green, and contains some lead",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"clear (no specific colour), and contains no lead"
  },
  { 
    "id":"efd0a91d-31c6-43de-aec8-2e8cc23653b9",
    "question": "Zero Fuel Weight (ZFW) is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the minimum permissible weight of fuel and oil required for a flight",
    "correctAnswer":"the maximum permissible weight of an aircraft with no disposable fuel or oil on board",
    "syllabusReference":"12.106.2(h)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:40:42.656245",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the maximum permissible weight of fuel and oil required for a flight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the minimum permissible weight of fuel and oil allowed at any time, taking into account the load factor of an aircraft"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4a8c0f7b-913a-4aab-9e36-9ede7a419604",
    "question": "  You are on approach to land and note that the PAPIs are displaying two white and two red lights. This indicates that;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"you are above the correct glideslope",
    "correctAnswer":"you are on the correct glideslope",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:40:58.069142",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"you are below the correct glideslope",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"you are using the glideslope meant for a heavier aircraft than the one you are flying"
  },
  { 
    "id":"87db942c-ecf8-4c33-bdf6-f39ec47d1298",
    "question": "In determining the landing distance (calculated by the pilot prior to landing), not less than how much of the tailwind component must be used in the calculation to comply with CAR Part 135?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"100%",
    "correctAnswer":"150%",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:36:40.173138",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"200%",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"85%"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3eca3b95-b2f8-44d5-88e5-79a657ae7fb1",
    "question": " Very bright runway lights;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"make the runway appear further away than what it actually is",
    "correctAnswer":"make the runway appear closer than what it actually is",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:07:48.891779",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"make the runway appear wider than it is",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"make the runway appear more narrow than it is"
  },
  { 
    "id":"75a41c92-ec41-401e-8f8e-689412f8fd23",
    "question": " According to section 27C of the Civil Aviation Act 1990, when must an aviation licence holder notify the Director of Civil Aviation about a change in their medical condition?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"When their doctor or medical examiner advises them that they no longer meet the medical standard of the medical certificate they hold",
    "correctAnswer":"When they are aware of, or have reasonable grounds to suspect, any change in their medical condition that may interfere with the safe operation of an aircraft",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:09:12.407440",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"When they begin taking any prescription-only medication",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"When they have received the results of a medical test, being a blood test or any other test, which shows a degradation of a previous medical condition"
  },
  { 
    "id":"23bfe907-f65d-428a-8441-4f39fefc4808",
    "question": " You are pilot in command of a scheduled air transport flight. One of your passengers is notably under the influence of alcohol. What does CAR Part 91 say about this situation?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"You must offload that passenger",
    "correctAnswer":"The passenger may be carried even where safety is likely to be endangered provided reasonable action is taken by the operator to minimise the risk",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:45:13.355359",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The passenger should be warned. no further alcohol served to them, and their behaviour monitored throughout the flight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Aviation Security or Police should be called and the passenger breath tested to ensure that they are under a safe limit to fly. If they are not, you must offload them"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9bc519da-2242-46cc-9339-a0d8edf60a94",
    "question": "An impulse coupling;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"generates a high voltage and increases the ignition timing",
    "correctAnswer":"generates a high voltage and retards the ignition timing",
    "syllabusReference":"12.20.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:36:11.581402",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"negates any voltage produced and increases the ignition timing",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"stablises any voltage produced and increases the ignition timing"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8a2a00cc-9a8b-4506-acbe-808dbae65034",
    "question": " Pursuant to CAR Part 1, 'controlled flight' means;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an Air Transport Operation, or an Air Operation, where passengers are carried",
    "correctAnswer":"any flight subject to an ATC clearance",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:37:30.387048",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"any flight where the aircraft is operating normally",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"any normal operation of a flight, including emergencies, but where such an emergency does not inhibit full control of the aircraft"
  },
  { 
    "id":"05b0a97a-88e9-431f-ba5a-e1a3425c68b4",
    "question": "  A memorised sequence of actions, which is stored in the long term memory, is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a skill",
    "correctAnswer":"a rule",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:11:57.745650",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"an attitude",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"knowledge"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e7eb40b2-b6f6-4002-8513-aeaa24b3a0a2",
    "question": "When radio silence is imposed following a MAYDAY call, this must be observed by all other stations until;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the pilot in command of the aircraft that transmitted the MAYDAY allows stations to transmit",
    "correctAnswer":"the controlling station allows normal transmissions",
    "syllabusReference":"2.14.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:37:44.712290",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"there has been a continuous period of 5 minutes or longer without any transmissions related to the MAYDAY situation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"there has been a continuous period of 10 minutes or longer without any transmissions related to the MAYDAY situation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f7f678e5-41d2-4747-aa2d-e9edcdc9dca0",
    "question": " If someone suffers from chronic fatigue;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"this should be cured by two consecutive good nights of sleep",
    "correctAnswer":"medical help will normally be required to assist in recovery from it",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:42:00.831369",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"it should not affect performance when piloting a flight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"this will have a sudden onset"
  },
  { 
    "id":"adabdbca-ae61-40ec-8b54-c5f9f1c5cc1d",
    "question": "The term \" QNH \" refers to the",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"ambient atmospheric pressure at a given datum",
    "correctAnswer":"atmospheric pressure from stations, reduced to mean sea level using ISA values",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:14:57.449306",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"altimeter subscale setting of 1013.2",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"atmospheric pressure from stations, reduced to mean sea level using atmospheric values"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1d525480-2a8b-4899-89fa-8c38d891d017",
    "question": "An anticyclonic system is always associated with;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a clockwise flow of air",
    "correctAnswer":"surface divergence",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:15:32.720407",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a tropical cyclone",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"surface convergence"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e7172bd0-3013-4983-b534-15b92d9d17e5",
    "question": "The 'accelerate-stop distance available' is defined as the length of the take-off run available and the length of any;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"clearway",
    "correctAnswer":"stopway",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:55:52.511128",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"any ground, clear of obstacles, and being sufficiently smooth to allow an aircraft to safely stop",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"apron"
  },
  { 
    "id":"daa1927a-a75c-4ce0-914d-520015076cbc",
    "question": "A memorised sequence of actions, a routine or procedure, that is stored in the long term memory is known as a;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"semantic occurrence",
    "correctAnswer":"rule",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:02:07.376514",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"knowledge",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"skill"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e434db69-71bb-448a-bfc1-a1e0c035830a",
    "question": "Cone cells in the eye",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"are sensitive to detail but not colour",
    "correctAnswer":"are sensitive to colour and detail",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:14:27.514014",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"are sensitive to colour but not detail",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"are not sensitive to colour or detail"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c955d0a1-7c67-4cfd-b316-a1720b007234",
    "question": "You are flying from Timaru to Christchurch. On leaving Timaru you correctly set an altimeter subscale of 1003 hPa and accurately fly at 1500 feet indicated on the altimeter. At Christchurch the QNH is 998 hPa. If you do not change your altimeter subscale setting, what altitude would you actually be flying at if you still flew at 1500 feet indicated?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1650 feet AMSL",
    "correctAnswer":"1350 feet AMSL",
    "syllabusReference":"6.12.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:43:41.821251",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"150 feet AMSL",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"1500 feet AMSL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2e3b1371-a6d4-4420-a61b-a725d86bd461",
    "question": " \"The altitude relative to standard atmospheric conditions at which the air density would be equal to the indicated air density at the place of observation,\" is the definition of;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"true altitude",
    "correctAnswer":"density altitude",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:13:35.008193",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"pressure altitude",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"transition altitude"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2f0d15cf-ba68-4a3f-874e-67632ac33ba8",
    "question": "Your radio is inop, and you see a steady green light as you approach the aerodrome. What does this mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Give way to other aircraft and continue circling",
    "correctAnswer":"Cleared to land",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:40:25.709594",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Return for landing (clearance to land and taxi will be given in due course)",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Land at this aerodrome and proceed to apron"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bae9a7ef-4c16-4135-bccc-dca6db5340ee",
    "question": "How can you verify whether an ELT has been activated?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The ELT will switch from ARM to the EMERG mode.",
    "correctAnswer":"A red flashing light on the ELT, and a siren signal being broadcast on 121.5 MHz.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.12",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 00:56:29.387039",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"A red flashing light on the ELT, and a siren signal broadcast on 119.1 MHz.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The transponder will automatically squawk 7700."
  },
  { 
    "id":"2ea0ca02-f772-4f3a-bb1d-7064b3baf168",
    "question": "The average height of the tropopause at the equator is approximately;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"36,000 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"52,500 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:31:26.298174",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"60,000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"29,500 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"7184db9a-6171-451d-b1c4-5c5432f77976",
    "question": " For the same air mass;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the Lifting Condensation Level (LCL) will be higher than the Convective Condensation Level (CCL)",
    "correctAnswer":"the Convective Condensation Level (CCL) will be higher than the Lifting Condensation Level (LCL)",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:37:17.941519",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the Lifting Condensation Level (LCL) will always be higher than the Dry Lapse Rate",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the Convective Condensation Level (CCL) will always be higher than the Saturated Lapse Rate (SLR)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5ff513bd-7615-46aa-b628-abd685152b57",
    "question": "Where can you find aerodrome frequencies?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"On Visual Planning and Visual Navigation Charts only.",
    "correctAnswer":"In AIPNZ Vol 4, and on Visual Planning and Visual Navigation Charts (VPCs and VNCs).",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(g)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:09:32.024838",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"On Visual Planning and Visual Navigation Charts (VPCs and VNCs), and Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAFs).",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"In AIPNZ Vol 4, and Notices to Airmen (NOTAMs)."
  },
  { 
    "id":"7577e669-c5f3-4b9f-9ff7-16ba6c7b78fb",
    "question": "An Emergency Locator Transmitter (ELT) must be inspected at least every;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"24 months or 200 hours, whichever is the sooner",
    "correctAnswer":"12 months or 100 hours, whichever is the sooner",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:47:26.457838",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"12 months or 200 hours, whichever is the sooner",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"24 months or 100 hours, whichever is the sooner"
  },
  { 
    "id":"21df5096-73cd-405a-b277-dfec712f11dd",
    "question": "The stages of acquiring a skill, in order, are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"knowledge, skill, automatic",
    "correctAnswer":"knowledge, acquisition, automatic",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:19:08.989726",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"acquisition, knowledge, automatic",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"skill, knowledge, automatic"
  },
  { 
    "id":"853849f4-2937-4df7-832a-ba5e316d18cf",
    "question": "Runway Visual Range (RVR) is defined as, \"the distance over which the pilot of an aircraft on the centreline of a runway can see the..\";",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"furthest distance beyond the aerodrome perimeter",
    "correctAnswer":"runway surface markings delineating the runway or identifying its centre line",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:26:37.396747",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"markings delineating the runway or its centre line, and the airfield beacon",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"runway lights, the runway, or the runway centre line"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a2cc40c7-7163-427a-a56c-04cbadb2b1d6",
    "question": " Diurnal pressure variation describes the natural variation of air pressure. It; ",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"occurs once daily and is more pronounced near the poles than at the equator",
    "correctAnswer":"occurs twice daily and is more pronounced near the equator than at the poles",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:17:36.520957",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"occurs twice daily and is more pronounced near the poles than at the equator",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"occurs once daily and is more pronounced near the equator than at the poles"
  },
  { 
    "id":"15ed52bd-daa7-4ac5-b799-c3d6ac2155c9",
    "question": "When water vapour changes state into ice;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"insolation is required",
    "correctAnswer":"latent heat is released",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:54:36.504119",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"albedo must not be present",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"diurnal variation is at its maximum"
  },
  { 
    "id":"40530d51-5e8e-48c6-815b-411db2eac20c",
    "question": "In an active ICTZ, typical weather conditions include;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"clear skies",
    "correctAnswer":"large numbers of CB, CU and AC clouds",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:39:04.962695",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"light and variable winds",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"mostly stratus type cloud"
  },
  { 
    "id":"27eab44c-ab23-4a54-b382-9f51b4468d7d",
    "question": "How would you select Mode A on a transponder?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Select the \"STBY\" (standby) setting.",
    "correctAnswer":"Select the \"ON\" setting.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:11:39.367465",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Select the \"ALT\" (altitude) setting.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Select the \"TST\" (test) setting."
  },
  { 
    "id":"4a8240fb-5d9c-4946-8500-44caacfd809b",
    "question": " An effective visual search technique involves;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"maintaining constant eye movement across the entire field of vision",
    "correctAnswer":"dividing the field of vision into 20 degree sectors and focusing on each sector for 2 seconds",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:37:32.494855",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"dividing the field of vision into a maximum of 20 slots which total the entire field of vision",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"dividing the field of vision into four or five sectors and focusing on each sector for 20 seconds"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8c0720de-56fe-4551-bea2-290c9776b212",
    "question": " The combination of factors that would likely give the greatest amplitude of a mountain wave is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"strong wind, low mountains and a gentle lee slope",
    "correctAnswer":"high mountains, where the width of the mountain ridges is equal to the wavelength of the mountain wave",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:09:45.886894",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"strong wind, low mountains, and where the width of the mountain ridges is equal to the one quarter the height of the mountain range",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"low mountains, where the width of the mountain ridges is equal to the wavelength of the mountain wave"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ea24c54d-d4da-494f-88fc-81dd9ab83260",
    "question": "You are planning a daytime cross country flight. Your aircraft burns 36 litres per hour and you expect your trip to take 2 hours and 33 minutes. Including legal reserves, what is the minimum fuel you need to carry?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"92 litres",
    "correctAnswer":"110 litres",
    "syllabusReference":"6.46.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:49:15.214438",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"94 litres",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"119 litres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8a586527-5509-4366-a0b6-01697c368dd0",
    "question": "What is the correct phraseology for an initial call from ZK-LJJ to Christchurch Tower?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"\"Lima Juliet Juliet, Christchurch Tower\"",
    "correctAnswer":"\"Christchurch tower, Lima Juliet Juliet\"",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(f)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:01:46.248825",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"\"Christchurch tower, response requested\"",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"\"Lima Juliet Juliet, how do you read?\""
  },
  { 
    "id":"6e4b85db-712f-46fb-8742-90e6c68c3ba2",
    "question": " The word \"monsoon\" means;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"rainfall",
    "correctAnswer":"season",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:51:46.575569",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"wet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"weather"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fd56bbac-0139-48e0-b5ba-9bb041816f4c",
    "question": "You're flying in controlled airspace under visual flight rules (VFR) and notice the screen on your transponder has gone blank. What should you do?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"No action is required if flying in controlled airspace under VFR.",
    "correctAnswer":"Immediately advise ATC.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.12",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 01:57:05.584812",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Squawk 7600.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Push the ident button to alert ATC."
  },
  { 
    "id":"0d2bfb30-f93f-4ddb-bc4d-00b53d7531c8",
    "question": "You get airborne out of Paraparaumu aerodrome on the way to Foxpine aerodrome to the north. What is the highest altitude you can fly without entering into controlled airspace?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"4,500 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"2,000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:34:08.309931",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"1,500 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"3,500 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e563dd0e-b0e1-474d-9b60-1b06d4f1709e",
    "question": " Due to friction, wind blowing over the sea is generally deflected by;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"30 degrees",
    "correctAnswer":"10 to 20 degrees",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:41:35.487502",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"wind is not deflected when it blows over the sea",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"40 to 60 degrees"
  },
  { 
    "id":"79459658-a02d-46c3-9db1-ff4e0475d125",
    "question": "A high Westerly Index suggests that;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the majority of the high pressure areas lie south west of New Zealand",
    "correctAnswer":"winds across New Zealand will predominantly be from the westerly quadrant",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:29:19.817260",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"areas of high pressure will form in the west, forming 'blocking anticyclones' which shield the western coast of New Zealand",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"winds across New Zealand will predominantly flow towards the west"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4281248d-1a23-4424-a470-1febb4da2bc5",
    "question": "What does a series of alternating red and green flashes mean when on the ground at an aerodrome?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Stop",
    "correctAnswer":"Danger, be on the alert",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:53:56.328359",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Taxi clear of landing area in use",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Return to starting point on aerodrome"
  },
  { 
    "id":"543a8071-ea72-44d7-8747-ade002fa9a12",
    "question": " How long is the clearway at the threshold of runway 13 at Mount Cook aerodrome?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"44 metres",
    "correctAnswer":"109 metres",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:05:03.677761",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"65 metres",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"115 metres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"09a12827-142d-4398-b6a5-012afdadaa29",
    "question": "What is the correct pronunciation of \"9\" in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Nine",
    "correctAnswer":"Niner",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:18:38.886596",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Nin",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Nought",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(c)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"adfaad31-05ea-4303-8ae7-b102c4d31416",
    "question": "A SIGMET is issued for a VA (Volcanic Ash) meteorological event. The validity period of this is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"twelve hours",
    "correctAnswer":"six hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:48:46.659701",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"reviewed after three hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"four hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2f81ab28-b0d5-4d18-8753-88dd8361e4ee",
    "question": " In the New Zealand latitudes, what height is low level cloud held to be?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Below 9,000 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"Below 7,000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:18:54.430049",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Below 10,000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Below 9,000 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fba8fb06-243c-4e1c-8482-b30e2849a105",
    "question": "  In the following TAF, issued in November, what surface wind can be expected at NZWF if the arrival time was 2000 hrs NZDT? \"TAF AMD NZWF 100437Z 1004/1011VRB02KT 20KM -RA FEW030 BKN050 FM100600 14012KT 20KM -RA BKN030 2000FT WIND 34020KT BECMG 1005/1007 16020KT =\"",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"160 degrees True at 20 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"140 degrees True at 12 knots",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:14:48.682483",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"340 degrees True at 20 knots",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Variable at 2 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f796da90-cfb5-47ab-b177-8693568f6e93",
    "question": "If you make a mistake during a radio call, what should you say before transmitting the correct message?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"MISTAKE",
    "correctAnswer":"CORRECTION",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(k)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:25:58.576737",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"I SAY AGAIN",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"ALTERATION"
  },
  { 
    "id":"398d8912-d644-4ae3-b6a0-3c3bc80affbe",
    "question": " In the SHEL(L) model, the 'E' stands for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the collective Experience of the whole crew",
    "correctAnswer":"Environment",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:09:36.103111",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Economy",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Experience of an individual Liveware"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b1523a56-edc5-49ae-9f13-18951d75f55d",
    "question": "In level flight, at a constant airspeed;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"drag is equal to thrust and lift is equal to the average of the drag, less the coefficient of weight",
    "correctAnswer":"lift is equal to weight and drag is equal to thrust",
    "syllabusReference":"12.60.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:38:56.014106",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"drag is equal to thrust and lift is the square of the coefficient of weight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"drag and thrust are equal, and lift balances the square of the coefficient of weight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a87287bd-e92c-4660-aab5-42a285be2dfa",
    "question": "The partial pressure of Oxygen in the lungs at sea level is approximately;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"150 mmHg",
    "correctAnswer":"102 mmHg",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:40:13.891133",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"125 mmHg",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"201 mmHg"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f7bffa2a-ded0-468c-9f3e-45c58802a787",
    "question": "The frequencies to be used when TIBA is activated can be found in which source?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Visual Navigation Charts",
    "correctAnswer":"NZ AIP Volume 4",
    "syllabusReference":"2.18.4(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:42:19.128402",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Instrument Navigation Charts",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Aerodrome Charts"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c8fff7dc-1a73-4543-a0f9-f9a7a94bd6e4",
    "question": "A Low Flying Zone;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"extends from the surface to 500 feet AGL and is active 24 hours per day provided there is visibility of 1500 metres or more",
    "correctAnswer":"extends from the surface to 500 feet AGL and is only active during daylight hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:29:56.930991",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"extends from the surface to 1000 feet AGL and is only active during daylight hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"extends from the surface to 1000 feet AMSL and is only active during daylight hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3bcb0211-b206-4c0a-bc9f-5038ddc055b0",
    "question": "What weather conditions are reported in the METAR \"METAR NZMF 230200Z 33006KT 20KM -SHRA FEW015 SCT040 BKN050 10/08 Q1008\"?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a surface wind of 330 degrees magnetic at 6 knots, there is presently a light shower of rain, and the lowest cloud is 1500 feet AMSL",
    "correctAnswer":"a surface wind of 330 degrees true at 6 knots, there is presently a light shower of rain, and the lowest cloud is 1500 feet AGL",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:51:24.573676",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a surface wind of 330 degrees magnetic at 6 knots, there is presently a shower of rain, and the lowest cloud is 1500 feet AMSL",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a surface wind of 330 degrees true at 6 knots, there is presently a shower of rain, and the lowest cloud is 1500 feet AGL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a524820b-8b7f-4604-a9c0-5c9ead74d192",
    "question": "A holder of an air operator certificate must keep accurate daily flight records for every aircraft unless;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the aircraft has undergone within the last 90 days a category 3 maintenance check",
    "correctAnswer":"the information is recorded in another document in a manner that enables the daily flight record details for every flight to be constructed",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:50:30.793205",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a summary document is kept in place of a full daily flight record",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"recording that information would lead to unnecessary delay and inhibit the operation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8438cd51-7806-4484-a558-2d91ceb74bf9",
    "question": "What does Readability Five mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Readable",
    "correctAnswer":"Perfectly readable",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(m)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:44:28.979994",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Readable, but with difficulty",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Readable now and then"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b14e86bb-fd7c-46c1-926a-e2d56c50d19c",
    "question": "You are in the cruise with a ground speed of 127 knots. How far will you travel in 24 minutes?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"32 nm",
    "correctAnswer":"51 nm",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:47:42.034626",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"28 nm",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"52 nm"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1018643d-5d4f-40f7-862e-d189af137aa1",
    "question": "In a typical four stroke aircraft engine, the four strokes, in order, are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"compression, induction, ignition and exhaust",
    "correctAnswer":"induction, compression, ignition and exhaust",
    "syllabusReference":"12.10.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:35:31.957435",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"compression, ignition, induction and exhaust",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"ignition, compression, exhaust and induction"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f9702da4-50f8-4ee9-8486-d5c8d954cd68",
    "question": "'Deviation' is the difference between;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"magnetic heading and true heading",
    "correctAnswer":"magnetic heading and compass heading",
    "syllabusReference":"6.14.2(f)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:44:04.075091",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"true heading and linear heading",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"compass heading and true heading"
  },
  { 
    "id":"894594fa-075b-469d-93ed-2a8668074ed0",
    "question": "Newton's third law can be expressed as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"force = mass x acceleration (f=m.a)",
    "correctAnswer":"for every reaction there is an equal and opposite reaction",
    "syllabusReference":"12.2.4(f)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:34:51.301141",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"every object in motion remains in that state unless acted upon by an external force",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"work = force x distance (w=f.d)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a9639be9-6f0c-44b2-a818-24dce6648c22",
    "question": "What does Readability One mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Readable now and then",
    "correctAnswer":"Unreadable",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(m)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:42:18.318710",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Readable, but with difficulty",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Readable"
  },
  { 
    "id":"cfeba608-4476-41b7-9a2e-aef56ef9a93e",
    "question": " The idea that people are more prone to make riskier decisions in a group situation is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"phlegmatic affect",
    "correctAnswer":"risk shift",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:02:54.942519",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"cognitive dissonance",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"teamwork"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1cf16c69-eca7-47ad-bfbb-4a1336f21094",
    "question": "The shape of the earth can best be described as a/an;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"oblique spheroid",
    "correctAnswer":"oblate spheroid",
    "syllabusReference":"6.2.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:52:17.633951",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"spheroid",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"circular"
  },
  { 
    "id":"65fb6cff-f485-44f6-b10a-7823bb6069b8",
    "question": "What does a steady red light gun signal mean when on the ground?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Taxi clear of landing area in use",
    "correctAnswer":"Stop",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:50:27.367412",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Return to starting point on aerodrome",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Danger, be on the alert"
  },
  { 
    "id":"50eb718c-2a4d-4805-8c39-e5e9f013cc2e",
    "question": "The type of ice which is most likely found in clouds with a high moisture content and at temperatures of between 0℃ and -20℃ is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"opaque ice",
    "correctAnswer":"clear ice",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:20:01.741446",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"hoar frost",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"rime ice"
  },
  { 
    "id":"29676dd2-d829-4006-8951-555f6d94f5a8",
    "question": "What weather conditions are reported in the METAR \"METAR NZMF 230200Z 33006KT 20KM -SHRA FEW015 SCT040 BKN050 10/08 Q1008\"?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a surface wind of 330 degrees true at 6 knots, there is presently a shower of rain, and lowest layer of cloud is 1500 feet AGL",
    "correctAnswer":"a surface wind of 330 degrees true at 6 knots, there is presently a light shower of rain, and the lowest layer of cloud is 1500 feet AGL",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:12:21.011765",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a surface wind of 330 degrees magnetic at 6 knots, there is presently a light shower of rain, and lowest layer of cloud is 1500 feet AMSL",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a surface wind of 330 degrees magnetic at 6 knots, there is presently a light shower of rain, and lowest layer of cloud is 1500 feet AMSL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"40ba0522-7d9f-4a48-ace1-efd43cf1c769",
    "question": " The vertical distance of a level, a point, or an object considered as a point, measured from a specified datum, and including the vertical dimension of an object, is the definition of;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"AMSL",
    "correctAnswer":"height",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:33:14.750737",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"obstacle clearance",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"elevation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"be879012-e215-44c8-9b78-c4da131136a3",
    "question": " The meteorological minima for an aeroplane engaged in a VFR air operation outside controlled airspace by night is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a ceiling of 1000 feet AGL and a visibility of 16km",
    "correctAnswer":"a ceiling of 3000 feet AGL and a visibility of 16km",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:43:07.275453",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a ceiling of 1000 feet AGL and a visibility of 5km",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a ceiling of 2000 feet AGL and a visibility of 5km"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5d94496f-8faa-40f8-b224-43327715b6ef",
    "question": "The semantic memory concerns;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"information from the five senses",
    "correctAnswer":"memories that have meaning",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:04:09.100731",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"overflow from the short term memory (STM)",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"memories about specific events"
  },
  { 
    "id":"667180f5-5e18-4a4a-a443-3c3be96d6b65",
    "question": " Oxygen enters the bloodstream via the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"stipules",
    "correctAnswer":"alveoli",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:02:29.436715",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"stipules",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"diaphragm"
  },
  { 
    "id":"279dd175-7f60-41d8-b150-6f92ec1d95e9",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true about communicating the time in radio transmissions?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Hours and minutes should always be transmitted.",
    "correctAnswer":"Only minutes are normally required, unless there is any possibility of misunderstanding, in which case the hour should also be included.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(e)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:52:56.436523",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Time transmitted in minutes is always referenced to the previous hour.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Time transmitted in minutes is always referenced to the next hour."
  },
  { 
    "id":"72de90f3-88c8-4987-9a50-77b85632e970",
    "question": "What is the correct pronunciation of \"decimal\" in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Decimal",
    "correctAnswer":"Day-see-mal",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(c)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:19:23.667280",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Dot",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Point"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8192f7a7-b5c2-4296-b5fd-4078175e444f",
    "question": "During the growing (or cumulus) stage of a thunderstorm;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"there are no draughts associated with this stage",
    "correctAnswer":"all draughts are upwards",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:34:31.267793",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"all draughts are downwards",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"draughts are both upwards and downwards"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b8e6b145-81fc-4648-9b92-9db7df0c2569",
    "question": " If a pilot means to raise the undercarriage but raises the flaps instead, this is an example of a;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"lapse",
    "correctAnswer":"slip",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:56:35.280671",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"mistake",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"violation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6716d92c-62df-44e7-ab01-37109ae38c61",
    "question": "When can an aircraft without an operable transponder operate in Transponder Mandatory airspace?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"When transiting in accordance with VFR cruising altitudes.",
    "correctAnswer":"With prior ATC approval, and complying with any conditions of that approval.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.12",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:21:54.549287",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"When maintaining a visual lookout for other traffic, where the pilot in command is responsible for separation.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"After notifying ATC."
  },
  { 
    "id":"049e293a-5454-46f4-a720-c89534599db4",
    "question": "You have a cold and elect to fly. Due to gases that may become trapped in your ears and sinuses, you may experience;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"hyperventilation",
    "correctAnswer":"pain during the descent",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:21:03.110440",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"hypoxia",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"pain during the ascent"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6cda06b1-dac1-45b6-83d2-b79ef610bdd3",
    "question": "The vertical distance of the terrain above mean sea level is referred to as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"QNH",
    "correctAnswer":"elevation",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:16:19.980667",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"altitude",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"height"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5576ee8c-8571-435a-86eb-6f2fd0f2f440",
    "question": "Following a particularly hard landing, you taxi in and prior to shutting down, you check 121.5. You note that you can hear an ELT operating and quickly determine that it is yours. You should;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"reset your ELT and notify CAA within 7 days",
    "correctAnswer":"reset your ELT, then notify the nearest ATS unit",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 09:56:10.913446",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"reset your ELT and inform the aircraft operator/owner",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"reset your ELT. As it is only a short term activation, similar to a test activation, no action will have been taken."
  },
  { 
    "id":"d7f50415-684f-4069-b643-4d5b5c5c0061",
    "question": "In a lost comms situation you see a steady red light gun signal while in the air, meaning...",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Aerodrome unsafe, do not land",
    "correctAnswer":"Give way to other aircraft and continue circling",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:42:00.189796",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Danger, be on the alert",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Return for landing (clearance to land and taxi will be given in due course)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1d67290d-74d8-41d3-a725-5b067e715b76",
    "question": "Virga is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the result of coalescence within an inversion",
    "correctAnswer":"precipitation that evaporates shortly after falling from cloud",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:35:24.548920",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the name given to ice crystals that have been caused to sublime",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the collective name for all types of precipitation that fall to the ground"
  },
  { 
    "id":"458f72f0-ff3c-4a67-b40d-8d51e8635f66",
    "question": "How can an automatic ELT be activated manually?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"By setting the remote ELT switch to the \"ARM\" position.",
    "correctAnswer":"By setting the remote ELT switch to the \"ON\" position.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.6(b)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:50:08.815845",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Automatic ELTs aren't able to be activated manually.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"By activating \"ARM\" mode directly on the ELT unit."
  },
  { 
    "id":"b62c5c01-bc1d-4949-ba6a-4b414bd34fa0",
    "question": "The eustachian tube;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"connects the semi circular canals to the auditory nerve",
    "correctAnswer":"connects the middle ear to the nasal passage",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:43:16.452429",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"connects the outer ear to the middle ear",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"connects the auditory nerve to the vestibular sacs"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e46fc9f9-2bc8-4c95-af6e-76e75fc83196",
    "question": " In respect of CAR Part 1, 'AD' is the abbreviation for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"accepted defect",
    "correctAnswer":"airworthiness directive",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:44:06.117026",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"aerodrome",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"automatic direction (finding equipment)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"97323fde-e2b5-410d-9df4-c2e13173b35d",
    "question": "The episodic memory;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"holds information for no longer than 8 seconds",
    "correctAnswer":"stores memories about specific events",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:18:40.809425",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"stores memories which have meaning",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"stores skills type information, which can be accessed without thinking"
  },
  { 
    "id":"97a33c4f-ae36-4da6-b6ef-4f87faf126d4",
    "question": "  The trade winds from the Northern and Southern hemispheres meet approximately in the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Horse latitudes",
    "correctAnswer":"Equatorial trough",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:21:17.222108",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"South Pacific Convergence Zone",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Mesoscale Convective Areas"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8efe778d-378b-4c0c-8839-3586b20977e9",
    "question": "Select the correct statement;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Pressure and density always increase with increasing altitude",
    "correctAnswer":"Pressure and density always decrease with an increase in altitude",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:15:30.629322",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Pressure and density always increase with an increase in temperature",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Density will always decrease if pressure increases"
  },
  { 
    "id":"37619286-2dd0-42ca-a36c-5cc09688d920",
    "question": " If a pilot carries out an operational flight check following maintenance and notes any defect during the flight, according to CAR Part 91, they must;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"discontinue the flight immediately and report the defect to the facility who carried out the maintenance work",
    "correctAnswer":"record any defect in the technical log",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:35:57.886346",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"make any entry to that effect in the flight manual",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"report the incident to the Director of CAA within 7 days"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8c93cce2-c1a8-41a1-9609-fb45c2585453",
    "question": "Which statement about the following SPECI is correct? \"SPECI NZWP 030320Z 01024G37KT 010V080 1500 -DZRA FEW002 BKN005 22/21 Q0995 RERA\"",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The lowest cloud is 200 feet above aerodrome level, and the wind direction is changeable through 010 and 080 degrees magnetic, gusting 24 to 37 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"Light drizzle and rain was falling at the time of the observation and there had been recent rain",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:10:49.398562",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Light drizzle is expected to fall sometime in the next one hour since it was issued, which is the validity time for a SPECI",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Drizzle had been falling but has now stopped, as indicated by the \" - \" symbol, and it had been raining recently"
  },
  { 
    "id":"dbf56756-4ba3-471d-a6bc-138338cbed91",
    "question": "The outside air temperature range in which carburettor ice may typically form is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"-10°C to + 20°C",
    "correctAnswer":"-15°C to + 25°C",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:32:20.407661",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"0°C to + 35°C",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"-5°C to + 30°C"
  },
  { 
    "id":"13d3dc5e-48db-4d4d-a4cc-3c4168b81b0f",
    "question": "How should the letter \"Z\" be said in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Zebra",
    "correctAnswer":"Zulu",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:14:21.045192",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Zee",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Zealand"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d9b33d67-be1d-4647-94de-c52b96ee7868",
    "question": "In addition to a mountain range of substantial proportion, the development of a fohn wind also requires;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a katabatic flow near the mountain range",
    "correctAnswer":"a wind blowing at, or near to, right angles to the mountain range",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:41:13.492603",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a super-adiabetic lapse rate within the air mass",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a dry and preferably warm air mass"
  },
  { 
    "id":"54bd7dcb-9875-4e54-b530-d710ea2060f9",
    "question": " You are flying across Cook Strait and become aware that your radios have completely failed. You should set your transponder code to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"7700",
    "correctAnswer":"7600",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:08:37.820880",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"7500",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"squawk ident"
  },
  { 
    "id":"189d3dc9-d151-4dc8-acab-16860406a348",
    "question": "How should the letter \"P\" be said in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Piper",
    "correctAnswer":"Papa",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:12:30.902082",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Pee",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Peter"
  },
  { 
    "id":"158fe5e6-8448-4596-8e3b-6e14fcc513c9",
    "question": "In the southern hemisphere, the Trade Winds are generally from which direction?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"North-east",
    "correctAnswer":"South-east",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:25:18.838623",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"North-west",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"South-west"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9d8d508c-d155-41c0-a7ff-bac2f44d6707",
    "question": "The 'best angle of climb' is the most altitude gained;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"for the least amount of time taken",
    "correctAnswer":"for the least distance covered across the ground",
    "syllabusReference":"12.62.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:39:16.001102",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"for the least amount of fuel used",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"for the greatest time taken"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f52f8f65-0838-4a98-836c-2c9231725f96",
    "question": "You are flying to an airfield for the first time, where the runway is longer than that of the airfield you usually fly at. What sort of illusion should you most likely be on guard for?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"that you are too high on approach",
    "correctAnswer":"that you are too low on approach",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:06:58.816036",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"break off phenomenon",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"false horizon affect"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ec1367d2-5be1-4d80-ac5b-a253f58278d3",
    "question": "Compared to a cold column of air, the pressure lapse rate within a warm column of air, is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"there is no correlation between temperature and pressure lapse rate",
    "correctAnswer":"lower",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:28:29.555909",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"higher",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the same"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3c72b509-d572-47f1-99ae-b7f0c9fce3cc",
    "question": "How would you select Mode C on a transponder?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Select the \"ON\" setting.",
    "correctAnswer":"Select the \"ALT\" (altitude) setting.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:12:13.541940",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Select the \"STBY\" (standby) setting.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Select the \"TST\" (test) setting."
  },
  { 
    "id":"a80fd49e-54e0-4c61-b0ae-11708cf83c81",
    "question": "  Cols are associated with;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"strong winds in winter and summer months",
    "correctAnswer":"extensive areas of fog during winter",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:19:43.401545",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"high pressure only",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"occluded fronts only"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ea8f6f02-c519-4251-a09e-8c5cddea4ce5",
    "question": "Prior to a warm front passing over an area, the weather to be normally expected is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"heavy, sudden and persistent rain, lasting upwards of 12 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"light rain, becoming heavy",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:28:58.226333",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"no precipitation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"icing conditions, particularly below the freezing level"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0032e323-6afe-47cd-a22f-1e2c0b285cac",
    "question": "Most of the temperature increase in the (i) is due to energy absorbed by (ii);",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"(i) troposphere, (ii) ozone",
    "correctAnswer":"(i) stratosphere, (ii) ozone",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:38:18.002018",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"(i) tropopause, (ii) aerosols",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"(i) mesosphere, (ii) aerosols"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4d37c292-18e2-4073-aede-300a807ce57d",
    "question": "You wish to fly VFR in uncontrolled airspace from Palmerston North to Auckland, a true track of 349 degrees. What altitude should you fly at to comply with the VFR cruising levels table?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"4500 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"5500 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"6.12.10",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:55:38.702454",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"5000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"8500 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f140e82d-2475-4024-8626-2b618657f124",
    "question": "The tropopause is the boundary between the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"mesosphere and stratosphere",
    "correctAnswer":"stratosphere and troposphere",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:47:21.736870",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"stratosphere and thermosphere",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"mesosphere and troposphere"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4a8e1d2a-cb70-4446-8177-e5d04eac55fe",
    "question": "Which of these does CAR Part 1 not directly specify as being a purpose of an Air Traffic Control service?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Preventing collisions between aircraft.",
    "correctAnswer":"Providing clearances for aircraft departing under Instrument Flight Rules (IFR).",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(k)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:51:35.113481",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Preventing collisions between aircraft and obstructions on any manoeuvring area.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Maintaining a safe and efficient flow of air traffic."
  },
  { 
    "id":"c03cd9a3-100a-4bc5-bd3d-3410be70a2e9",
    "question": "Looking at Visual Navigation Chart (VNC) C13, what is the straight line distance between Timaru and West Melton aerodromes?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"142 nm",
    "correctAnswer":"71 nm",
    "syllabusReference":"6.6.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:53:49.553409",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"72 nm",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"140 nm"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b1737472-868d-45d6-ad7d-c7f918716008",
    "question": "The Coalescence theory of rainfall states that;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an absence of ice nuclei, thereby causing supercooled water droplets, is the major contributor to rainfall in the polar regions",
    "correctAnswer":"rain is formed by water droplets fusing together with other droplets inside cloud, before these droplets fall from the cloud",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:16:52.103309",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"due to the saturation vapour pressure of ice, ice particles can grow by sublimation, instead of water droplets forming",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"virga is precipitation falling from a cloud and evaporating prior to reaching the ground"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0a3d33e5-9b84-462e-bd56-666decb4a243",
    "question": "  If there is a simultaneous stimulation of two of the semi-circular canals, the illusion that may result is known as the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"somatogyral illusion",
    "correctAnswer":"cross coupled turning (coriolis) effect",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:38:49.397025",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the leans",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"somatogravic illusion"
  },
  { 
    "id":"23c96d4b-686d-4ecf-bb45-61a4751311ee",
    "question": "The maximum all up weight of an aircraft is 2500 pounds. Approximately how many kilograms is this?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"240 kg",
    "correctAnswer":"1140 kg",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.18(d)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:59:22.878981",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"550 kg",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"220 kg"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5dc5542e-a7c1-431f-9eb4-9d93e78eb665",
    "question": "What ends when the centre of the sun is 6 degrees below the celestial horizon?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Morning Civil Twilight (MCT)",
    "correctAnswer":"Evening Civil Twilight (ECT)",
    "syllabusReference":"6.18.2(f)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:56:11.639550",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Sunlight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Sunrise"
  },
  { 
    "id":"851822cf-464d-4cd5-bb47-e337e1b9a953",
    "question": "You are flying towards an airfield where you intend to land. As you are just about to enter the MBZ in which your destination airfield is located, your radio fails completely. What should you do?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Continue to your original destination airfield",
    "correctAnswer":"Divert to an aerodrome outside the MBZ",
    "syllabusReference":"2.16.4(c)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:39:22.890549",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Transmit a PAN PAN call",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Divert to the nearest controlled aerodrome and squawk 7700"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bce2ce4e-c4e9-4d78-9303-d6c577ffad0e",
    "question": "In a standard recovery from a developed stall;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"full opposite rudder is used to stop the rotation and thus break the stall",
    "correctAnswer":"the check forward breaks the stall, full power is used to reduce the rate of descent and opposite rudder stops the rotation",
    "syllabusReference":"12.68.18",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:32:32.977949",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"full power is used to break the stall, after which ailerons are used to level the wings",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the application of full rudder and partial power is suggested so that maximum aerodynamic loading is not exceeded"
  },
  { 
    "id":"571b19f7-5c17-4e79-9422-ce1cc11c011a",
    "question": "The large scale convective cell which, in part, has air returning to the earth in the subtropics, is the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"ITCZ",
    "correctAnswer":"Hadley cell",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:27:12.120724",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Ferrell cell",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Polar cell"
  },
  { 
    "id":"851b77cf-e01a-47ab-a811-814c7cf9036c",
    "question": "As people get older they suffer hearing loss, with hearing becoming less acute particularly with;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"hearing sounds from behind",
    "correctAnswer":"the high frequency range",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:13:59.828161",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the low frequency range",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"hearing sounds from in front"
  },
  { 
    "id":"60373101-8022-4c40-9d0d-378bfa268d78",
    "question": " The normal currency period for a class 1 medical certificate, for a 61 year old pilot engaged in single crew air transport operations carrying passengers, is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"24 months",
    "correctAnswer":"6 months",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:30:52.687644",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"12 months",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"60 months"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ce475b24-8c50-4486-bc38-22d4aa8baa9e",
    "question": "Part 91 requires New Zealand registered aircraft to carry an Aircraft Emergency Location System (AELS) at all times when flying in the New Zealand Flight Information Region (NZ FIR) with some exceptions. Which of these is a valid exception?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"During day VFR below 10,000 ft AMSL.",
    "correctAnswer":"Ferry flights from where an operator takes possession of an aircraft to a place where the AELS is to be installed.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.4",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:18:10.012045",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"When flying in non-mountainous terrain.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"When flying within 25 NM of the departure aerodrome."
  },
  { 
    "id":"e0645760-c1e6-496c-b0a7-bdb7c3827db3",
    "question": "If you set mode Alpha on your transponder then;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the transponder will be in standby mode",
    "correctAnswer":"it will not transmit any altitude information",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.4(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:30:45.453157",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"it will transmit only the aircraft True Airspeed",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"it will transmit only the aircraft Indicated Airspeed"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c0503e03-f8f8-435c-9eb6-58884edb4e16",
    "question": " After donating blood, a pilot should wait how long before flying?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"12 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"24 hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:06:21.603835",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"48 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"96 hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"686c6989-a9d4-4dec-8b16-d605380b93ca",
    "question": "You take off from an airfield which is 165 feet AMSL with the correct QNH of 1008 set. Upon landing at your destination, which is 45 feet AMSL, your altimeter reads 315 feet AMSL. Assuming a standard pressure change of 1 hPa per 30 feet, what is the correct QNH at your destination aerodrome?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1017 hPa",
    "correctAnswer":"999 hPa",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:39:32.825971",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"998 hPa",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"1018 hPa"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9816888d-ba1c-4c05-b36d-1b02047c7577",
    "question": "Separation of traffic is provided by ATC in which situation?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Between IFR flights in class G airspace",
    "correctAnswer":"Between IFR and VFR traffic in class C airspace",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:42:45.896274",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Between IFR and VFR traffic in class G airspace",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Between IFR and VFR traffic in class D airspace"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a351958c-dbdd-467e-8267-6c976a3019f8",
    "question": "  A memorised set of routines which is learnt with practice and can be carried out without conscious thought is known as a;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"rule based behaviour",
    "correctAnswer":"skill based behaviour",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:15:13.148627",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"knowledge based behaviour",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"automatic based behaviour"
  },
  { 
    "id":"53f76145-7a22-4062-a857-da27e969e9a5",
    "question": "The type of ground which receives the maximum amount of insolation in mid afternoon on a summer's day will be;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"ground with an elevation of more than 2000 feet AMSL",
    "correctAnswer":"western facing mountain slopes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:28:53.120646",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"flat ground",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"eastern facing mountain slopes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"aefe38ec-3f04-4584-a2ab-e733e811e5f8",
    "question": " A student pilot (who does not hold a pilot licence) may not fly solo in an aircraft unless, among other requirements, that person has;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"shown proficiency on a ZFT simulator or equivalent, if they have not flown within the last 30 days",
    "correctAnswer":"piloting experience in an appropriate aircraft within the immediately preceeding 30 days",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:09:44.760181",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"all PPL written examination credits",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"passed an oral or written test, administered by an A or B category instructor, if they have not flown for more than 30 days"
  },
  { 
    "id":"14955363-9d6f-4a74-957f-4ae81dd2d0ef",
    "question": "In the phonetic alphabet, the word QUIZ is spelt;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Quazar - Uruguay - India - Zulu",
    "correctAnswer":"Quebec - Uniform - India - Zulu",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:31:54.054361",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Quest - Uruguay - India - Zoo",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Quest - Uniform - India - Zulu"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b29e10d2-abb7-4e85-89da-46cc0b7bf0de",
    "question": "You are flying downwind in the circuit at a controlled airfield. The control tower signals you with alternating red and green flashes. The meaning of this signal is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"vacate the circuit and remain in an orbit overhead the field at 1500 feet AGL",
    "correctAnswer":"danger, be on the alert",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:04:30.056917",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"land at this aerodrome and proceed to the apron",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"continue approach (and expect a further signal for clearance to land)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"49ca679d-de04-4d3b-b9c3-2d5b74755a83",
    "question": " The warming of valley walls, particularly those east facing, through solar radiation and subsequent heating of the air through conduction, causes;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"convection, which causes Fohn winds",
    "correctAnswer":"convection, resulting in an Anabatic wind",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:39:03.713246",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"conduction, allowing for a lower air pressure and therefore a semi-diurnal wind",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"convection, resulting in a Katabatic wind"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6d37fd62-7d0e-4904-abf9-aee2adbacb67",
    "question": " \"Albedo\" refers to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the shape of a surface",
    "correctAnswer":"the amount of radiation that is reflected by a surface",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:34:16.662598",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the amount of radiation that is absorbed by a surface",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the colour of a surface"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b2b939bc-8e92-4e6e-90aa-fe692c8f9cb8",
    "question": " In the SHEL(L) model, the peripheral Liveware refers to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the non-physical part of the system",
    "correctAnswer":"human-to-human interaction, including management and supervision",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:05:03.062470",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the limitations of human-to-human interaction",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the human element or operator"
  },
  { 
    "id":"30ac911d-5563-4bf8-aa2c-e767d7e063ed",
    "question": " Buys Ballot's Law states that, in the southern hemisphere, if you stand with your back to the wind, the area of high pressure is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"behind you",
    "correctAnswer":"on your left",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:34:01.808508",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"in front of you",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"on your right"
  },
  { 
    "id":"39d8414e-9330-4095-b717-d8e6d7c71e48",
    "question": " You are flying to an airfield for the first time, where the runway is wider than that of the airfield you usually fly at. What sort of illusion should you most likely be on guard for?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The runway may give the illusion of you being higher than you are, and you may not level off early enough",
    "correctAnswer":"The runway may give the illusion of you being closer than you are, and you may level off too early",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:57:13.554928",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The approach to land may seem too steep",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The approach to land may seem too shallow"
  },
  { 
    "id":"807e9da8-8fb7-4713-8b1c-ccf5dd27157a",
    "question": "If you have been diving to a distance of 8 metres. It is recommend that you should not fly for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"6 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"12 hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:21:55.794920",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"24 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"no length of time. You may fly immediately"
  },
  { 
    "id":"14fd4c6b-2b3c-4f30-830a-e215257657bd",
    "question": " You are pilot in command of a piston engined aircraft, carrying passengers, and operating as part of an Air Operation. You need to refuel the aircraft. Your passengers;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"may be on board during refueling but you are responsible to ensure their safety and wellbeing during the refuelling",
    "correctAnswer":"must not be on board when the aircraft is being refueled",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:40:31.732862",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"may not be on board if the refuelling operation if the refuelling operation is intended to, or it is believed that it will, take longer than 30 minutes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"may be on board if all are able bodied - that is, all are able to independently exit the aircraft without help"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a494eef3-41ec-4a35-bbb3-d8805c0bc1b8",
    "question": "What does the phrase \"How do you read?\" mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Confirm ready to copy clearance.",
    "correctAnswer":"What is the readability of my transmission?",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:45:27.016087",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Do you have charts available for the aerodrome?",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Are you able to comply with my last transmission?"
  },
  { 
    "id":"39cecf0c-6c56-4a1c-830f-76c351cb6e91",
    "question": "In the southern hemisphere the northern end of a magnetic (and therefore a compass needle) will want to point upward. This is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"magnetic variation",
    "correctAnswer":"magnetic dip",
    "syllabusReference":"6.4.6(j)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:52:46.953707",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"magnetic deviation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"magnetic direction"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6e5ac2ff-dad3-4946-be20-d2d06f2e789f",
    "question": " Stimulation of the otolith organs can result in the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the leans",
    "correctAnswer":"somatogravic illsuion",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:17:22.169268",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"cross coupled turning (coriolis) effect",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"somatogyral illusion"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d50b3438-c0cb-499d-b96b-9bb18d458003",
    "question": "What does \"BREAK BREAK\" mean in a radio communication?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Indicates separation of parts of a message to the same aircraft.",
    "correctAnswer":"Indicates a separation between messages transmitted to different aircraft.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:31:20.689076",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Instructs an aircraft to initiate the \"break\" portion of the standard overhead rejoin.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Instructs an aircraft to immediately alter course to avoid oncoming aircraft traffic."
  },
  { 
    "id":"5e324380-55e5-4289-a1aa-6cec467ccff6",
    "question": "  One advantage of group decision making is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"fewer number of problem solving approaches",
    "correctAnswer":"reduced individual bias and prejudice",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:21:27.636525",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"it takes less time to come to a decision",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"less likelihood of risk shift"
  },
  { 
    "id":"eb2d29fe-bcf9-4a50-a089-4e85e1868a58",
    "question": "The factors combining to give the highest density altitude are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"lower temperature than ISA, high water vapour content of air, higher air pressure than ISA",
    "correctAnswer":"higher temperature than ISA, high water vapour content of air, lower air pressure than ISA",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:41:50.280605",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"lower temperature than ISA, high water vapour content of air, lower air pressure than ISA",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"higher temperature than ISA, low water vapour content of air, lower air pressure than ISA"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8487c510-b3f1-44f7-831f-83207c33284b",
    "question": " The term 'threshold' denotes;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the point where a 1:50 obstacle-fee approach surface intersects the runway surface",
    "correctAnswer":"the point where a 1:20 obstacle-fee approach surface intersects the runway surface",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:38:24.634529",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the end of the runway, but does not include any clearway or stopway that may be present",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the point where an aircraft would touch down on the runway after a normal approach and after clearing the 50 foot height over the aerodrome fence"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b1e68bf5-0ee6-44ec-9b3b-e2e256e62897",
    "question": "At low-levels in the mid latitudes, the dry adiabatic lapse rate is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1.5℃ per 1000 feet gain in height",
    "correctAnswer":"3℃ per 1000 feet gain in height",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:29:50.871632",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"1.98℃ per 1000 feet gain in height",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2℃ per 1000 feet gain in height"
  },
  { 
    "id":"faafbbc4-539c-4e82-b559-5d17ddf83f06",
    "question": "  The airfield lighting system that consists of a very high intensity uni-directional light projector located on either side of the runway approximately 30m from the runway extended centre line and downwind of the landing threshold, is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Runway Landing Threshold Lighting (RTHL)",
    "correctAnswer":"Runway End Indicator Lighting (REIL)",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:42:16.437758",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Runway Touchdown Zone Lighting (RTZL)",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Runway Edge Lighting (REDL)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c8f53507-c535-4704-8f99-cb2037815fcb",
    "question": "While flying from A to B you are tracking 045 degrees True, holding 4 degrees of right drift. Due to bad weather you need to return to your origin. Assuming the wind is the same, what is correct reciprocal True heading to return to A?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"225 degrees",
    "correctAnswer":"229 degrees",
    "syllabusReference":"6.38.2(c)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:59:46.952148",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"246 degrees",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"221 degrees"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c86bc4cf-c57d-4691-a1ee-2d0bdb8eea6e",
    "question": " Prior to a warm front passing over an area, the weather to be normally expected is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"no precipitation",
    "correctAnswer":"light rain, becoming heavy",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:10:29.439131",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"heavy, sudden and persistent rain, lasting upwards of 12 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"icing conditions, particularly below the freezing level"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9d157c5c-ebfb-4fae-b11a-be4baf008178",
    "question": "The primary radio frequency for communicating with Napier control tower is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"109.9",
    "correctAnswer":"124.8",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:42:29.209785",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"119.1",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"125.6"
  },
  { 
    "id":"616eb4d9-3893-4a99-ae45-46533e7c1f32",
    "question": "You have asked for a \"radio check\" as you believe that your radio may be transmitting an unclear signal. A station replies back that they hear you \"strength 3\". This means that your transmission is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Readable now and then",
    "correctAnswer":"Readable but with difficulty",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(m)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:34:45.560334",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Readable",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Perfectly readable"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4de81add-749a-4a66-9580-9ebe4414b378",
    "question": "The correct name for a line joining points of equal magnetic variation is a/an;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"isobar",
    "correctAnswer":"isogonal",
    "syllabusReference":"6.4.6(k)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:53:08.873653",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"lumbar",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"contour"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d9fc9579-498a-480d-98bc-08210a391470",
    "question": "What is the correct method of operation for a handheld microphone?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Place the handheld microphone in its cradle, press the Push To Talk (PTT) button on the microphone, transmit your message, and release the PTT button",
    "correctAnswer":"Hold the microphone close to your mouth, press the Push To Talk (PTT) button on the microphone, transmit your message, and release the PTT button",
    "syllabusReference":"2.4.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 10:15:24.092763",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Hold the microphone close to your mouth, press the Push To Talk (PTT) button on the control yoke, transmit your message, and release the PTT button",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Hold the microphone close to your mouth, click the Push To Talk (PTT) once to activate the transmission, transmit your message, then click the PTT button again to end the transmission"
  },
  { 
    "id":"94cf67f3-f00b-46f8-8264-b3536cfb1b11",
    "question": "110 nm is equal to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"59 km",
    "correctAnswer":"127 statute miles",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.18(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:48:28.600946",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"115 statute miles",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"125 statute miles"
  },
  { 
    "id":"995b1a74-fe3a-4633-9c8b-c5a9851f7c79",
    "question": "Calibrated Air speed (CAS) is Indicated Airspeed (IAS) corrected for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"temperature and density error",
    "correctAnswer":"instrument and position error",
    "syllabusReference":"6.8.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:42:41.215790",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"heading and airspeed error",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"static and pressure error"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5fbf802d-8f7e-4f46-b5df-9c0b314ad111",
    "question": "You are are flying ZK-ABC and intending to carry out a touch and go on runway 07 at Rangiora aerodrome, which is unattended. You mistakenly transmit \"Rangiora traffic, ABC is downwind zero-seven, full stop.\"  What should you know do?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Transmit: \"Touch and go\"",
    "correctAnswer":"Transmit: \"Correction, ABC is downwind zero-seven, touch and go\"",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(k)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:33:36.841510",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"No further transmission is necessary as it will be obvious when you conduct the touch and go that you are not stopping",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"No correction is necessary as the aerodrome is unattended"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3d4a44c3-8e73-451b-94be-7f83c2a928d5",
    "question": "What is the name given to describe the situation with an intensified Walker circulation caused by a higher pressure than usual in the east near the coastline of South America?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Humboldt current",
    "correctAnswer":"La Nina",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:47:45.172344",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Negative ENSO index",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"El Nino"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1e617c36-4ac3-4d7d-b2e1-ee8249af5fcf",
    "question": "At a given pressure, moist air is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"more dense than dry air",
    "correctAnswer":"less dense than dry air",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:30:52.301528",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"more likely the cause of turbulence",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"less likely the cause of turbulence"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e60dbb2e-f4f3-4277-a49a-5f453dc018a9",
    "question": "The SPECI \"SPECI NZWP 030320Z 01024G37KT 010V080 1500 -DZRA FEW002 BKN005 22/21 Q0995 RERA\" was issued by NZWP. Which statement about it is correct?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Light drizzle is expected to fall sometime in the next one hour since it was issued, which is the validity time for a SPECI",
    "correctAnswer":"Light drizzle and rain was falling at the time of the observation and there had been recent rain",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:17:09.570532",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Drizzle had been falling but has now stopped, as indicated by the \" - \" symbol, and it had been raining recently",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The lowest cloud is 200 feet above aerodrome level, and the wind direction is changeable through 010 and 080 degrees magnetic, gusting 24 to 37 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3916b645-0187-4ec4-8226-e03db162ce57",
    "question": "By definition, a 'flight level' is a surface of constant atmospheric pressure, expressed in terms of hundreds of feet, that is related to a specific datum of 1013.2 hPa and is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"correlated to the ICAO cruising altitude table",
    "correctAnswer":"separated from other such surfaces by specific pressure intervals",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:49:53.192936",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"separated from other such surfaces by assigned cruising datums",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"determined by winds aloft predictions and significant weather events"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4443d4c3-86db-4ff5-a4a3-75421813f794",
    "question": "The time system used in aviation is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Uncoordinated Time Constant",
    "correctAnswer":"Co-ordinated universal time",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(e)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:32:53.615724",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Universal Time Constant",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Local Mean Time"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6a6e754f-b5fd-416e-9642-27b92e831a2a",
    "question": "  The ambient temperature at 20 000 feet AMSL is -35℃. What is the ISA height at that temperature?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"17 500 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"25 000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:20:24.586959",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"10 000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"70 000 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2e14ca86-e4c1-4156-9da8-096228cd8c7b",
    "question": "  The air that is warmed through contact with the earth's surface is warmed by;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"convection",
    "correctAnswer":"conduction",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:21:41.302190",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"albedo",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"insolation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"066d269b-78c9-4b84-9e06-3d0227555333",
    "question": " The tendency to accept only information which backs up a hypothesis or idea is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"perception bias",
    "correctAnswer":"confirmation bias",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:04:46.079152",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"expectation bias",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"experiential bias"
  },
  { 
    "id":"caab44ea-00c4-4f69-a6e7-b3e461597e1f",
    "question": "The average height of the tropopause in the mid-latitudes is approximately;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"60,000 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"36,000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:49:47.738181",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"52,500 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"29,500 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"eebc004e-88d5-4bca-824a-b152c3d328d9",
    "question": " You are flying towards Rangiora aerodrome and hear an aircraft report that they are taking off from Rangiora and will be carrying out manoeuvres within the \"vicinity of the aerodrome.\" If that pilot is using the term correctly, they are intending to operate; ",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"within the aerodrome traffic circuit",
    "correctAnswer":"not more than 10 nm laterally from Rangiora airfield",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:48:42.792657",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"not more than 15 nm laterally from Rangiora airfield",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"no specified distance from the aerodrome but are intending to re-enter the Rangiora circuit without further warning"
  },
  { 
    "id":"51cc4328-88d4-4726-bbf2-ca0dbb8fefc2",
    "question": "You have a cold and elect to fly. Due to gases that may become trapped in your ears and sinuses, you may experience;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"pain during the ascent",
    "correctAnswer":"pain during the descent",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:43:42.172520",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"hypoxia",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"hyperventilation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6e5d9e92-8f62-4fb1-8b4f-3034a1b9ba23",
    "question": "When the squelch control is turned all the way up (fully clockwise)",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"almost all signal will be filtered out, including voice transmissions",
    "correctAnswer":"very little unwanted noise is filtered, and considerable static is likely to be heard",
    "syllabusReference":"2.4.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 10:10:22.187867",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"only unmodulated signals can be sent",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"your voice is more likely to be transmitted clearly"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b93b42e2-a555-47bb-98e7-ff22c1da0232",
    "question": "A METAR AUTO contains the line \"21009KT 9999 OVC021/// 09/06\n\". This indicates that;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the sensor is faulty and is unable to detect the cloud type",
    "correctAnswer":"cloud is detected but the type (TCU or CB) cannot be determined",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:25:00.484620",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"cloud type is not reported if the cloud is reported as overcast",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"visibility is not reported due to a faulty sensor"
  },
  { 
    "id":"76ed6e9c-aad9-4ae7-837b-cb055ee77a0c",
    "question": "What is the definition of \"aerodrome traffic circuit\"?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The circuit direction and altitude as published on an aerodrome chart.",
    "correctAnswer":"The pattern flown by aircraft operating in the vicinity of an aerodrome.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(g)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:42:20.862576",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"A prescribed route for IFR aircraft arriving at an aerodrome on a visual approach.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"A standard set of radio calls for aircraft operating in the vicinity of an aerodrome."
  },
  { 
    "id":"9db08a37-b338-47bf-87e8-87e833116d87",
    "question": " A high westerly index over New Zealand can be seen on a weather map by the presence of;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a deep trough of low pressure seated to the south of New Zealand",
    "correctAnswer":"several areas of high pressure to the north of New Zealand",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:10:09.998713",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a 'family of lows' to the north of New Zealand",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a blocking anticyclone to the west of New Zealand"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1cfb7841-bae3-41e6-a408-96a76d502b20",
    "question": " If you have been diving to a distance of 15 metres, you should not fly for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"6 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"24 hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:36:40.688346",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"48 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"12 hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b8171763-339b-49f5-9c16-e33e72857223",
    "question": "  You are flying across Cook Strait and become aware that your radios have completely failed. You should set your transponder code to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"squawk ident",
    "correctAnswer":"7600",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:46:14.671159",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"7500",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"7700"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f6cf703b-2d19-4997-a1ad-c3045a6053cb",
    "question": "The two types of Radar in use in New Zealand airspace are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Primary and Secondary. Both interrogate the transponder in an aircraft",
    "correctAnswer":"Primary and Secondary. Only Secondary radar interrogates the transponder in an aircraft",
    "syllabusReference":"6.72.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:57:25.277630",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Secondary and Tertiary. Only Secondary radar interrogates the transponder in an aircraft",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Secondary and Tertiary. Only Tertiary radar interrogates the transponder in an aircraft"
  },
  { 
    "id":"785fe9d8-8021-4bf2-91cc-b91eb299b875",
    "question": "In CAR Part 1, what does \"Act\" refer to?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Civil Air Act 1990",
    "correctAnswer":"Civil Aviation Act 1990",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:14:29.914957",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"CAR Part 91",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"CAR Part 61"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1deb7047-dfcc-44eb-855e-47eb7b9a53f1",
    "question": "When preflighting an aircraft with an automatic ELT, what position should the remote ELT switch be in before starting a normal flight?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"ON",
    "correctAnswer":"ARM",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.6(b)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:51:57.716551",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"OFF",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"STBY"
  },
  { 
    "id":"17aed01f-d9f8-4a0d-abdd-ef1a0b855a80",
    "question": "To increase the range of your radio transmissions, you could fly;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Lower",
    "correctAnswer":"Higher",
    "syllabusReference":"2.2.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:26:40.407592",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Slower",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Faster"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ac1a55f5-7698-4001-88ec-0cad49751412",
    "question": "What term is used to indicate an error was made in a previous communication, and the correct information follows?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Alteration",
    "correctAnswer":"Correction",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:33:19.772423",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Modification",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Reconfirm"
  },
  { 
    "id":"280c00a0-6021-4d25-a5a2-06ae8d01d0d4",
    "question": "Following a forced landing in a remote area, you should;",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Ensure the ELT is ON. It's safe to turn the ELT off after approximately 10 minutes to conserve battery, because this will have given the RCCNZ centre long enough to locate the signal.",
    "correctAnswer":"Ensure the ELT is ON, and leave it ON until rescued.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.8",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:56:51.247001",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Set the ELT to ARM. Only change the ELT to ON when rescue personnel are in the vicinity.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Disable the ELT to prevent any risk of an electrical fire."
  },
  { 
    "id":"65ad2dff-359e-4a1d-8a91-33fa8b3a1a8f",
    "question": "Is cruising flight permitted at altitudes between 13,000' AMSL and FL150?",
    "authorName":"Pete Russell","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"No, these altitudes are only available for transition to and from flight levels.",
    "correctAnswer":"Yes, in controlled airspace with ATC approval.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.72.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-23 20:04:35.563367",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"At any time, but only at odd altitudes plus 500 feet on northerly headings, and even altitudes plus 500 feet on southerly headings.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"At any time, but only at odd altitudes plus 500 feet on southerly headings, and even altitudes plus 500 feet on northerly headings."
  },
  { 
    "id":"cbd9e0f5-9273-4ee6-85e9-0d577c0c5a11",
    "question": "What is an \"alerting service\"?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"An air traffic service provided at aerodromes operating with an Aerodrome Flight Information Service (AFIS) to alert airborne aircraft of potential traffic conflicts.",
    "correctAnswer":"An air traffic service provided to notify appropriate organisations regarding aircraft in need of search and rescue aid.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(n)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:59:37.860289",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"An air traffic service provided at controlled aerodromes to alert emergency services as needed in the vicinity of the aerodrome.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"An air traffic service provided to alert VFR aircraft of traffic conflicts when operating with flight following."
  },
  { 
    "id":"143231e1-a8e4-4358-aa77-efa213fd1df2",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"All persons working anywhere at an airport",
    "correctAnswer":"Any persons operating in support of the pilots and air traffic controllers",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 09:58:05.351016",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"All airline employees",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"All persons whose normal course of business has them visiting an airport",
    "question": "Civil Aviation Rules made pursuant to the Civil Aviation Act 1990 may require which of the following persons to hold an aviation document?"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1dbbfff7-076b-4609-9695-dd818ef9b295",
    "question": "You take off from Hamilton and track to Tauranga aerodrome. In respect of altimeter settings;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the pressure altitude setting should be used once clearance to enter Tauranga CTR is given",
    "correctAnswer":"the advised Tauranga QNH should be set on entry to Tauranga CTR",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:39:33.310284",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Area QNH should be set throughout a flight once you have vacated the Hamilton CTR",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the Hamilton CTR QNH, used as a reference, should be set throughout the flight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"967fa661-ba7c-442e-9eed-17a86281e810",
    "question": "What does Readability Two mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Unreadable",
    "correctAnswer":"Readable now and then",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(m)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:42:40.395846",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Readable, but with difficulty",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Readable"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b787623d-57a6-4ca8-a851-7426bc416893",
    "question": "To avoid a collision or near miss, aircraft approaching head on shall;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the aircraft on a northerly magnetic heading shall climb slightly, while the aircraft on a southerly heading shall descend slightly",
    "correctAnswer":"both alter course to the right",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:31:31.367881",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"both alter course to the left",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"both alter course so that they keep the other aircraft on their right"
  },
  { 
    "id":"991a1fa1-1c19-4880-9f62-73198d603743",
    "question": "What sort of weather conditions can be expected in New Zealand when El Nino conditions prevail?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Predominant wind from the south-southwwest, cooler weather on the west coast and warmer weather in the east",
    "correctAnswer":"Predominant wind from the west-southwest, wetter weather on the west coast and drier weather in the east",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:27:37.976090",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Predominant wind from the north-northeast, wetter weather on the east coast and drier weather in the west",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Predominant wind from the east-northeast, wetter weather on the east coast and drier weather in the west"
  },
  { 
    "id":"406fba70-4949-4082-8723-b4794b5142db",
    "question": "A pilot working on Special Operations must record each flight in their logbook within;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"24 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"7 days",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:37:13.974558",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"48 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"14 days"
  },
  { 
    "id":"24a7a432-d673-4942-90a3-ff8bbd12e376",
    "question": "You are at top of descent and must descend 8,000 feet in 17 minutes. What is your required rate of descent in feet per minute?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"212",
    "correctAnswer":"460",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.8",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:58:42.012364",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"280",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"128"
  },
  { 
    "id":"64f4837a-8096-435f-8205-bd2ec4ec2939",
    "question": "The purposes of oil in an engine are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"removal of water and to promote the flow of fuel through the engine block",
    "correctAnswer":"reduction of friction, removal of small solids, and cooling",
    "syllabusReference":"12.32.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:37:02.117032",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"removal of small solids, cooling, and enhancing airflow around the exhaust manifold",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"cooling and provision of an operating manifold"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e66eb58d-3ccf-4255-9b3a-e0da22d42da9",
    "question": "You're on the ground at a towered aerodrome with an inoperative radio, and see a steady green light gun signal. What does this mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Cleared to taxi",
    "correctAnswer":"Cleared for take-off",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:49:52.612399",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Return to starting point on aerodrome",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Taxi clear of landing area in use"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a9e2204b-5eb6-4c51-9942-8f957ab64410",
    "question": "  Aeroplanes operating under Part 135 and engaged in VFR air operations by day may not use an aerodrome for take off or landing unless;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the width of the runway strip is at least two and a half times the the aircraft wing span, or 40 metres, whichever is greater",
    "correctAnswer":"the width of the runway strip is at least two and a half times the the aircraft wing span, or 30 metres, whichever is greater",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:35:27.985798",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the width of the runway is at least two and a half times the the aircraft wing span, or 40 metres, whichever is greater",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the width of the runway is at least two and a half times the the aircraft wing span, or 30 metres, whichever is greater"
  },
  { 
    "id":"22830edf-fcca-461c-b732-63d7cd702ce6",
    "question": " Having established communications with an aerodrome tower, your radio suffers a fault and while it can transmit an unmodulated signal, it can no longer transmit your voice. The tower clear you to a waypoint. On arrival at that position, how many times should you activate your transmitter?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"twice",
    "correctAnswer":"four times",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:44:20.951591",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"once",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"three times"
  },
  { 
    "id":"19aaae5c-e364-419b-acd9-5924a9787782",
    "question": "What is the definition of \"aerodrome elevation\" according to AIP GEN?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The elevation of the highest point of the aerodrome.",
    "correctAnswer":"The elevation of the highest point of the landing area.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(e)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:34:40.731078",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The average elevation of the landing area.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The average elevation of the aerodrome."
  },
  { 
    "id":"b5958aa5-6ce5-4056-8cac-88ccaaa173c8",
    "question": "You are flying at a pressure altitude of 7000  feet. The outside air temperature is -10℃ and your IAS is 120 knots. What is your TAS?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"128 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"131 knots",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:47:24.534935",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"133 knots",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"136 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1342746d-0d48-49c2-832d-8ee24e845ccd",
    "question": " What ICAO definition of turbulence would an aircraft and its occupants be experiencing if there was more or less persistent and abrupt movement of the aircraft around its three axes?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Severe",
    "correctAnswer":"Moderate",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:18:06.561013",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Little",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Slight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ea88a81f-dec6-47a4-a271-9e7e89b0651d",
    "question": "In respect of wind direction;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Wind direction is always in degrees true in a SPECI, and degrees magnetic in an METAR",
    "correctAnswer":"Wind direction is always in degrees true in a TAF, and degrees magnetic in an ATIS",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:46:31.751638",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Wind direction is always in degrees true in a METAR, and degrees magnetic in a TAF",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Wind direction is always in degrees magnetic in a METAR, and degrees true in an TAF"
  },
  { 
    "id":"898e032d-fc59-4fea-94d1-935eab46e3f1",
    "question": "You wish to transit through military operating area M302 in Taranaki. Which statement is correct?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"You must obtain permission prior to entry by contacting Taranaki District Council by telephone",
    "correctAnswer":"You must obtain permission prior to entry by contacting Ohakea Approach on 125.1 or by telephone",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:44:37.930906",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"You must obtain permission prior to entry from NZ Defence Force by telephone",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Permission is not needed to enter but it is advisable to contact ATC prior to entry"
  },
  { 
    "id":"428733cc-d3fb-41bf-bfc8-5b1cd14d8e7b",
    "question": "How can you identify airspace where a transponder is required?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"On an aerodrome plate, denoted by the term \"position transmitting equipment required.\"",
    "correctAnswer":"On a Visual Navigation Chart (VNC), denoted by the letters \"TM\".",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.10",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:17:37.928624",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"A transponder is required in all airspace in the NZ FIR.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"By checking the conditions required for entry into a MOA."
  },
  { 
    "id":"3f36abce-8a2b-4d98-b5d0-581a15ce1f7c",
    "question": " The meteorological minima for VFR flight outside controlled airspace below 10,000 feet AMSL is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"separation of 1,000 feet vertically and 8km horizontally from cloud, and not less than 5km visibility",
    "correctAnswer":"clear of cloud and in sight of the surface, and a minimum of 5km visibility",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:06:48.378815",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"separation of 1,000 feet vertically and 2km horizontally from cloud, and not less than 8km visibility",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"separation of 500 feet vertically and 5km horizontally from cloud, and not less than 5km visibility"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9760db8b-86cd-41ed-86cf-ffb9e95381dc",
    "question": "In respect of air density;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"moist air is lighter than dry air, so more can occupy a given volume, therefore its density is higher",
    "correctAnswer":"moist air has a lower density than dry air",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:40:45.705595",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"dry air has a lower density that moist air",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"moist air has a higher mass than dry air and so the density of moist air is higher"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5191050d-9e34-41f7-822f-6c843e1dfed4",
    "question": " If a pilot misidentifies a problem and puts in place the wrong procedure, this is a failure of a;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"overload based behaviour",
    "correctAnswer":"rules based behaviour",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:58:22.215544",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"skills based behaviour",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"knowledge based behaviour"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f77b6e7d-aef7-4a24-a7af-a59711d3dcb2",
    "question": "You're flying LJC and tower transmits \"Lima-Juliet-Charlie, you're now number two for landing\" (which doesn't require a readback). What is the correct response?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"\"Wilco, Lima-Juliet-Charlie.\"",
    "correctAnswer":"\"Lima-Juliet-Charlie\"",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(j)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:35:31.115389",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"\"Number two, roger. Lima-Juliet-Charlie.\"",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"\"Affirm\""
  },
  { 
    "id":"b31709ca-9657-4189-8066-a4dc9ba5c546",
    "question": "A risk matrix contains a risk probability and a __________ value for each risk?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"evaluation",
    "correctAnswer":"severity",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:20:36.516341",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"likelihood",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"development"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4027e3e7-ce55-4f75-bc97-875a11ec0e2e",
    "question": " To be eligible to act as pilot in command of a multi engined aircraft on air operations, a pilot must have completed;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"25 hours and 10 take offs and landings",
    "correctAnswer":"10 hours and 10 take offs and landings",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:37:52.215434",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"5 hours and 5 take offs and landings",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"15 hours and 10 take offs and landings"
  },
  { 
    "id":"853a9ee7-bb93-4bdd-b29c-e00036cbdf2c",
    "question": "'Density altitude' is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the altitude at which the air pressure and air density are the same",
    "correctAnswer":"the altitude in the ISA which has the same air density as the actual altitude",
    "syllabusReference":"12.100.12",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:40:21.260704",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"calculated by determining the pressure altitude and then adding the humidity value",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"calculated once an aircraft is established in straight and level flight at an altitude above 10,000 feet AMSL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"36fc0a0d-eef0-4400-b079-20825c7cfe12",
    "question": "One nautical mile is equal to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the distance covered by 1 minute of longitude on the surface of the earth, measured along a meridian",
    "correctAnswer":"the distance covered by 1 minute of latitude on the surface of the earth, measured along a meridian",
    "syllabusReference":"6.6.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:50:34.074291",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the distance covered by 1 minute of longitude on the surface of the earth, measured along a parallel",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the distance covered by 1 minute of latitude on the surface of the earth, measured along a parallel"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5a876113-3f1f-4920-8ecc-5da71ee45cb0",
    "question": "When a transponder is in standby (STBY) mode, which of the following is true?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The transponder transmits only identification and position information.",
    "correctAnswer":"The transponder is on, but won't respond to interrogation.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 08:54:33.884546",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The transponder transmits altitude, but not position information.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The transponder transmits only the identification (squawk code) when interrogated."
  },
  { 
    "id":"623fb73c-adb9-4543-b08f-55ecedef7833",
    "syllabusReference":"2.4.4(a)",
    "authorName":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:30:23.673128",
    "examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"is above your eyeline so that it picks up other voices in the aircraft cabin",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"is below your chin, so that your voice is easily picked up by the microphone",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"is above your eyeline so as not to interfere with your vision",
    "question": "A boom microphone should be adjusted so that it",
    "correctAnswer":"just touches your lips when they are pursed"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d4f7eed9-1420-4ae7-8f9b-73294b70a376",
    "question": "  In a southern hemisphere tropical cyclone, which quadrant of the cyclone has the worst wind and weather?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"right forward quadrant",
    "correctAnswer":"left forward quadrant",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:15:55.485907",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"left rear quadrant",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"right rear quadrant"
  },
  { 
    "id":"73c4d26d-4eac-4cae-9847-bc3793cf7176",
    "question": " You are tasked to fly an aeroplane on a Part 135 flight and will do so through class G airspace at an altitude of 2500 feet and by day. The visibility and cloud ceiling minima are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"8km visibility and cloud 1500 feet AGL",
    "correctAnswer":"5km visibility and cloud 1000 feet AGL",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:43:45.131148",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"8km visibility and cloud 1000 feet AGL",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"5km visibility and cloud 1500 feet AGL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0b26d46a-4d6f-4cc3-b8cf-c6e82f082170",
    "question": "After a cold front has passed over an airfield, what changes can be expected?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Precipitation will stop and the temperature will be warm",
    "correctAnswer":"Pressure will increase and the relative humidity will be lower than prior to the front arriving",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:09:12.234543",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"High and low level cloud will clear and vizibility will be good due to no precipitation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Wind strength will slowly increase and the dew point will be higher than prior to the front arriving"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f74f2f40-1bbc-4c57-9c07-7daa5e014751",
    "question": "What frequency/frequencies does an ELT transmit on?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"121.5 MHz only.",
    "correctAnswer":"121.5 MHz and 406 MHz.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:02:43.771608",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"111.00 MHz and 406 MHz.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"406 MHz only."
  },
  { 
    "id":"5bb5acd1-4084-4cd0-9621-a0606e4cb634",
    "question": "What is the most important to remember when entering a squawk code into the transponder?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Not to accidentally select 1300, 1400, or 2200.",
    "correctAnswer":"Not to accidentally select 7500, 7600, or 7700.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:04:13.459399",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Ensure the transponder squelch is set correctly.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The code 1200 should always be entered when flying VFR."
  },
  { 
    "id":"dde360c9-d40f-4934-bb65-d3c58390d923",
    "question": "What begins when the centre of the sun is 6 degrees below the celestial horizon?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Evening Civil Twilight (ECT)",
    "correctAnswer":"Morning Civil Twilight (MCT)",
    "syllabusReference":"6.18.2(e)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:51:10.454169",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Daylight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Sunlight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"14667c75-c918-4b80-87a5-6cb3911eaf9c",
    "question": "For radiation fog to form it requires;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an already cold surface and can form over sea and land areas",
    "correctAnswer":"a cooling surface and will only form over land areas",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:17:08.150127",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a cooling surface and can form over sea and land areas",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"an already cold surface and will only form over land areas"
  },
  { 
    "id":"97d5a5d4-3339-419d-8193-10278bf1f55d",
    "question": "The pressure gradient is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the change of Corilois force, measured from high to low",
    "correctAnswer":"the change of pressure with horizontal distance, measured from high to low",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:17:31.870389",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the change of Corilois force, measured from low to high",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the change of pressure with vertical distance, measured from high to low"
  },
  { 
    "id":"40c680ad-4e07-48f1-bd3c-c4d546b97d73",
    "question": "What is the correct way to transmit the time \"1020\"?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Ten twenty",
    "correctAnswer":"One zero two zero",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(e)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:55:16.078036",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Four zero before",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"One zero twenty"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4e5dd1ce-3d26-4631-a7ae-389178d1cb30",
    "question": "A westerly wind is blowing across a mountain range running north-south with a height of 6000 feet. The temperature at sea level on the west is 12℃ and the dew point is 6℃. Following precipitation on the west coast, the dew point on the eastern side of the ranges is 3℃. What will the temperature at sea level be on the eastern side of the ranges?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"16 ℃",
    "correctAnswer":"15 ℃",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:13:11.933011",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"14 ℃",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"13 ℃"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ae5976d7-5770-4141-bbbd-fc45243a8cbb",
    "question": "Night vision is easily lost when looking at a bright light because;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the fovea retracts when exposed to bright light",
    "correctAnswer":"rhodopsin in the eye is easily destroyed by bright light",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:40:39.535986",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"rod cells are easily destroyed by bright light",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"cone cells are easily destroyed by bright light"
  },
  { 
    "id":"119df919-46c9-4dfe-9fda-06b42b65ad7f",
    "question": "The pressure gradient is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the change of Corilois force, measured from low to high",
    "correctAnswer":"the change of pressure with horizontal distance, measured from high to low",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:28:28.070647",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the change of Corilois force, measured from high to low",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the change of pressure with vertical distance, measured from high to low"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1bcecceb-bbcd-4272-940a-42353b6c51bd",
    "question": "To comply with CAR Part 91 in respect of simulated instrument flight;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"dual controls must be fitted and a flight plan must be filed or a flight following arrangement must be made",
    "correctAnswer":"a safety pilot must be present and they must have adequate vision forward and to each side",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:51:04.833162",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a safety pilot must be on board and an appropriate means of communicating with the person undergoing simulated instrument flight must be available",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a safety pilot must be present and their controls must be able to override those of the person undergoing the simulated instrument flight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bb69f462-6c52-4a1f-8387-d650cda30c51",
    "question": "A stable atmosphere will produce what sort of clouds?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Towering cumulus, Cirrostratus and Stratus",
    "correctAnswer":"Cirrus, Altostratus and Cirrostratus",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:53:54.697126",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Cirrus, Cirrostratus and Cirrocumulus",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Cirrus, Cirrocumulus and Nimbostratus"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5e5f9bdb-57e9-42a5-9d7c-e326ffd49956",
    "question": "You are flying on a magnetic heading of 045 degrees and wish to make a compass turn onto a heading of 180 degrees.  Magnetic variation is 20 degrees East and you are at a constant airspeed.  When performing the compass turn, you should roll out on what compass heading?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"210 degrees",
    "correctAnswer":"150 degrees",
    "syllabusReference":"12.38.6(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:37:51.793875",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"130 degrees",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"190 degrees"
  },
  { 
    "id":"854b3191-376d-4175-a907-3d7e01b0a75f",
    "question": " The equipment required to legally fly VFR at night in a powered aircraft, pursuant to CAR Part 91, includes;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a illumination sufficient for maps and charts to be read easily by all crew members",
    "correctAnswer":"illumination for each required instrument and indicator, and an anti-collision light system",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:46:54.112101",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a landing light and position (navigation) lights",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a torch for each crew member and an artificial horizon indicator (AHI)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fd445d59-8034-4e32-b3c3-4d2406c4eae7",
    "question": "The normal vertical separation provided by ATC in class C airspace is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1000 feet below FL210 and 2000 feet above FL210",
    "correctAnswer":"1000 feet below FL290 and 2000 feet above FL290",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:48:03.492361",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"2000 feet below FL290 and 1000 feet above FL290",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2000 feet below FL210 and 2000 feet above FL210"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5ddd947f-0889-402f-b4ed-8c869eaf7ab6",
    "question": " On the lee side of a mountain range in fohn wind conditions, the wind will be;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"cold and moist",
    "correctAnswer":"warm and dry",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:31:18.153425",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"cold and dry",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"warm and moist"
  },
  { 
    "id":"612c0faa-b012-4880-9f38-50cc427933e8",
    "question": "A disadvantage of Very High Frequency (VHF) signals are that they",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"are more susceptible to static interference than HF signals",
    "correctAnswer":"are limited to line-of-sight",
    "syllabusReference":"2.2.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 09:24:14.835811",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"require radio equipment only available on modern aircraft",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"can be disturbed by sky waves, causing a loss of reception"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0102687f-437e-4b09-b688-5055ac0eff93",
    "question": " An AIREP is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an aviation report issued in respect of significant weather events that are forecast to occur",
    "correctAnswer":"an automated weather report transmitted by an aircraft back to a ground station",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:29:41.777129",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a reported observation by the pilot of an aircraft that is relayed to an ATC unit",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"an aviation report issued in respect of significant weather events currently occurring"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4ae4fad9-b148-412a-b659-a5d3dc4bec8a",
    "question": "A notice containing information that relates to flight safety, air navigation, technical, administrative or legislative matter but which does not qualify for the origination of a NOTAM or for inclusion in the AIPNZ, is a/an;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"aeronautical information service",
    "correctAnswer":"aeronautical information circular",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:03:09.855890",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"aeronautical information publication",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"AIP supplement"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bfcbd816-1435-42aa-b5ad-429e41aeb8ce",
    "question": "When flying in Class B, C, or D airspace...",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Two-way communications are required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace, unless flying on an IFR flight plan.",
    "correctAnswer":"Two-way communications are required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace, unless authorised.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(c)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:32:09.522571",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Two-way communications are always required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Two-way communications are required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace, unless flying an aircraft equipped with dual ADSB transmitters."
  },
  { 
    "id":"8871fdc5-c50a-464a-981c-77db2e98c187",
    "question": "What does the term \"ROGER\" mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"I will comply with your last transmission.",
    "correctAnswer":"I have received all of your last transmission.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:35:59.451685",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"This is the end of my transmission.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"\"Yes\"."
  },
  { 
    "id":"323d6500-5fd3-4533-bcc1-121461b9457a",
    "question": "  An aircraft may develop a turn without the pilot noticing. The turn may then develop into a high speed, tight, descending turn, and the pilot senses only the descent and not the turn. This is an example of the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"cross-coupled turning (coriolis) effect",
    "correctAnswer":"somatogyral illusion",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:17:46.954206",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"somatogravic illusion",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the leans"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1b0d357a-abad-496e-8297-7b84ed2ed34b",
    "question": "You're in the air with an inop radio. You have been circling when you see a series of green flashes from the tower's light gun. What does this mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Cleared to land",
    "correctAnswer":"Return for landing (clearance to land and taxi will be given in due course)",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:43:44.371122",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Land at this aerodrome and proceed to apron",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Danger, be on the alert"
  },
  { 
    "id":"54f65319-e3f4-4df3-a597-e1d6e17149b6",
    "question": "Night vision is easily lost when looking at a bright light because;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the fovea retracts when exposed to bright light",
    "correctAnswer":"rhodopsin in the eye is easily destroyed by bright light",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:06:45.477755",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"cone cells are easily destroyed by bright light",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"rod cells are easily destroyed by bright light"
  },
  { 
    "id":"7fd11fa9-912d-4635-bd7c-14e09f0934fa",
    "question": "When flying at the boundary between two different classes of airspace, you must comply with the requirements of...",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The more restrictive class of airspace.",
    "correctAnswer":"The less restrictive class of airspace.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(c)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:34:20.444989",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The more restrictive class of airspace, unless operating with VFR flight following.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The less restrictive class of airspace, unless operating in a formation flight."
  },
  { 
    "id":"d246a553-ae86-4fbf-96ea-b40a2435b7c7",
    "question": "A phlegmatic type personality is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"sad",
    "correctAnswer":"not easily ruffled",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:16:20.148823",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"happy or bubbly",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"angry"
  },
  { 
    "id":"84897a2f-1a25-4d54-95eb-ce65930dc054",
    "question": "  Except when operating close to an aerodrome with a known QNH, or commencing an instrument approach into that aerodrome, zone QNH should be used when in uncontrolled airspace and;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"above 13000 feet AMSL",
    "correctAnswer":"below 13000 feet AMSL",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:38:25.587477",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"below 13000 feet AGL",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"above 13000 feet AGL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f3406440-06f3-43a2-ad39-823d85fc2d53",
    "question": "At 18,000 feet the partial pressure of the atmosphere is approximately;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"one quarter of sea level pressure",
    "correctAnswer":"half of sea level pressure",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:18:08.849512",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the same as at sea level",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"three quarters of sea level pressure"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2542af02-bab7-42da-84fc-ff5bcbb4a932",
    "question": "What does a series of white flashes from a light gun mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Cleared to land",
    "correctAnswer":"Land at this aerodrome and proceed to apron",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:46:39.447534",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Give way to other aircraft and continue circling",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Danger, be on the alert"
  },
  { 
    "id":"484a3251-4e63-44d3-b070-5425b3e79b42",
    "question": "By definition, fog is reported when there is cloud on the surface and the visibility is; ",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"more than 1000 metres but less than 8000 metres",
    "correctAnswer":"less than 1000 metres",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:29:21.686322",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"more than 1000 metres but less than 5000 metres",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"less than 5000 metres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2b428b74-6ea7-464e-8ae3-1d551d1859bc",
    "question": "Rod cells in the eye;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"can perceive colour but cannot perceive detail",
    "correctAnswer":"cannot perceive colour or detail",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:37:56.594051",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"can perceive both colour and detail",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"cannot perceive colour but can perceive detail"
  },
  { 
    "id":"846de28a-1dd8-4073-b9c9-3e3d02bb4194",
    "question": "A METAR AUTO contains the line \"21009KT 9999 OVC021/// 09/06\". This indicates that;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"visibility is 9999 metres",
    "correctAnswer":"visibility is 10km or greater at the sensor",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:24:54.999786",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"visibility cannot be determined by the sensor",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the sensor is detecting significant differences in visibility depending on direction and caution should be exercised"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a427589d-ed0a-40e7-80d3-5af038b7d07f",
    "question": "Decompression sickness (\"the bends\") is caused by;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Nitrogen being excreted from the body via gas exchange in the lungs",
    "correctAnswer":"Nitrogen coming out of solution and into the body's tissues",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:42:26.732211",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Oxygen and Nitrogen displacing other gases within the blood stream and joints",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the partial pressure of Oxygen being less than that in the body and so allowing Oxygen to leach into the body's tissues, especially in the joints"
  },
  { 
    "id":"468e5f59-d628-4a37-95c1-e6a008a35873",
    "question": " The holding of conflicting beliefs or ideas at the same time is known as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"confirmation bias",
    "correctAnswer":"cognitive dissonance",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:05:56.637509",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"perception bias",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"metacognition"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3e75363b-13d5-43b3-8f41-885d2d32401f",
    "question": "The angular difference between magnetic direction and compass direction is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"variation",
    "correctAnswer":"deviation",
    "syllabusReference":"6.4.6(l)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:49:56.614049",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"bearing",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"dip"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2590e31f-f5d7-4654-ac83-1aa7d04c9e98",
    "question": "What does Readability Four mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Readable now and then",
    "correctAnswer":"Readable",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(m)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:44:01.936491",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Readable, but with difficulty",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Perfectly readable"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4fda84ce-39cc-44fd-9097-be37d2a8fe28",
    "question": " The time of usual consciousness without Oxygen at 25000 feet is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"15 to 30 minutes",
    "correctAnswer":"3 to 5 minutes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:58:59.075503",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"45 to 60 seconds",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"1 to 2 minutes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1e40017b-e3a8-4e12-842e-355a268fde45",
    "question": "The two-seat Cessna 152 you've rented to practice circuits in has an inoperative ELT. Are you able to go ahead with the flight?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"No, the only flight that would be allowed is a ferry flight to have the ELT fixed.",
    "correctAnswer":"Yes, an Aircraft Emergency Location System (AELS) isn't required on a two-seat aircraft if operating within 10 nm of the aerodrome it took off from.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.4",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:25:05.960927",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Yes, an ELT is only required if carrying more than one person.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"No, an ELT is always required in the New Zealand Flight Information Region (NZ FIR)."
  },
  { 
    "id":"e1b79b9d-3b49-4e60-ab56-61c3e099ea23",
    "question": "When a traveler's body functions remain on home time and so do not occur at the same time as those of people at the destination, they may be said to have;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"acute fatigue",
    "correctAnswer":"circadian dysrhythmia",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:20:10.955955",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"sensory threshold",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"narcolepsy"
  },
  { 
    "id":"08266640-636c-4ede-9d1d-ea0fb53fedad",
    "question": "Your aircraft is loaded with 144 kg of usable aviation gasoline.  Assume that the aircraft burns a constant rate of 25 litres per hour for all stages of flight. What is your maximum endurance?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"345 minutes",
    "correctAnswer":"480 minutes",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.14",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:59:04.211756",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"575 minutes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"750 minutes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2e1651d7-b9e9-4f62-a1b8-1324e4bc36d2",
    "question": "The eustachian tube;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"connects the outer ear to the middle ear",
    "correctAnswer":"connects the middle ear to the nasal passage",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:13:29.435646",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"connects the semi circular canals to the auditory nerve",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"connects the auditory nerve to the vestibular sacs"
  },
  { 
    "id":"14c52038-c1e6-4d61-a0c3-020a8ba65288",
    "question": "A parcel of air at 10 degrees Celsius is lifted into the atmosphere where the temperature is 15 degrees Celsius, and remains at 10 degrees Celsius. That lifted parcel of air;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"is unstable as it has been able to be lifted to a higher level in the atmosphere",
    "correctAnswer":"is stable, and will want to return to its original level when the lifting force is removed",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:16:43.649925",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"is conditionally stable, as it has been able to be lifted to a higher level in the atmosphere",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"is partially stable, and will remain at the new level until forced to return to its original level"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9e0dc749-cae7-4cd1-83af-a970431fe156",
    "question": "You are flying from Kaikoura to Wellington at a constant indicated altitude. The temperature at Kaikoura is 18 degrees Celsius and as you fly north it gradually decreases approaching Wellington, where it is 10 degrees Celsius. Which statement is most correct?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Your altimeter will begin to under read as you near Wellington",
    "correctAnswer":"You altimeter will begin to over read as you near Wellington",
    "syllabusReference":"6.12.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:55:15.353196",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Temperature has no affect on an altimeter",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Temperature will only affect a non-calibrated altimeter"
  },
  { 
    "id":"aa4e0e21-1052-42eb-9c22-7b9dab4bd83d",
    "question": "The term \"fitness to fly\" refers to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a pilot's physical fitness only",
    "correctAnswer":"a pilot's mental and physical fitness",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:44:38.217113",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a pilot's mental fitness only",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a pilot's ability as a pilot"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bdb3f9e5-49db-44ae-b425-7bb342cc9852",
    "question": "You want to depart on a VFR flight but have snow and some ice adhering to the wings of your aircraft. Which statement is correct?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"If the take off is performed in accordance with the aircraft flight manual, you may take off",
    "correctAnswer":"You would be in breach of CAR Part 91 if you took off",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:44:56.351583",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Provided you use the appropriate anti-icing equipment provided on the aircraft, you may take off",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Provided the snow and ice is not on the control surfaces, you may take off"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c17d738f-fb55-48aa-a3f6-e2c344e25d1e",
    "question": " An aircraft may develop a turn without the pilot noticing. The turn may then develop into a high speed, tight, descending turn, and the pilot senses only the descent and not the turn. This is an example of the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"somatogravic illusion",
    "correctAnswer":"somatogyral illusion",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:45:02.073272",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"cross-coupled turning (coriolis) effect",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the leans"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0bcd06a5-4cab-4a5c-ac56-970306b403c7",
    "question": "You carry out a forced landing into a paddock within New Zealand and no radio or phone coverage is available. The symbol you would use to indicate to any aircraft overhead that you are fine and that no immediate help is required, is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a smiley face",
    "correctAnswer":"LL",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.10",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:35:38.698778",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"XX",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"XXX"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b39acaa2-698a-40fd-a8eb-a3d77b92ec2d",
    "question": "What is the correct pronunciation of \"5\" in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Five",
    "correctAnswer":"Fife",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:18:17.645801",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Fif",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Flight",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(c)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"625d7cb8-e016-4cd8-b696-ccafcd8a9a45",
    "question": " An 'alerting service' means;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a Flight Information Service at an aerodrome or Flight Information Officer coordinating a Flight Information Region",
    "correctAnswer":"an air traffic service provided to notify organisations regarding aircraft in need of search and rescue",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:39:21.988041",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"an air traffic control service provided for controlled flights in controlled airspace",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the company, pilot or individual who first notifies other agencies of an aircraft in distress"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2a6fe8bf-8db8-42eb-9609-2d1c3fcd98ad",
    "question": " A person with a current pilot licence may perform limited maintenance on an aircraft, subject to conditions. One of these conditions, set out in CAR 43, is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"special tooling is provided for the task required",
    "correctAnswer":"the aircraft being used on Air Operations does not have a MAUW greater than 5700kg or more than 10 passengers",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:45:39.111800",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the aircraft being used on Air Operations does not have a MAUW greater than 7550kg or more than 12 passengers",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the aircraft is not used on any Air Operation"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f0611ecd-3fe3-49a2-828e-0d933ae5209b",
    "question": "In the New Zealand latitudes, what height is middle level cloud held to be?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"5000 feet to 17000 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"7000 feet to 17000 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:27:54.486384",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"7000 feet to 20000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"5000 feet to 20000 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"13422462-ec6f-48da-9d09-f9b331efde19",
    "question": "If your ELT has inadvertently been activated, what is the correct procedure for disarming the ELT?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Turn the ELT switch to ARM for up to 5 seconds, then back to ON. Notify ATC and the RCCNZ as soon as possible.",
    "correctAnswer":"Turn the ELT switch to ON for up to 5 seconds, then back to ARM. Notify ATC and the RCCNZ as soon as possible. ",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.12",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 01:00:16.110083",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The ELT will automatically deactivate if no impact is detected within 5 minutes. Notify ATC and RCCNZ as soon as possible.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Squawk 1200 and notify ATC of the inadvertent activation."
  },
  { 
    "id":"58f49356-5556-4b7c-bf62-54c590d879dd",
    "question": "What is the correct term to indicate \"No\"?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"No",
    "correctAnswer":"Negative",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:41:39.476511",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Standby",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Roger"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f1fbc7f1-76f9-4d45-bb32-e1f2dad4267a",
    "question": "According to the definition of an \"aerodrome\" in AIP GEN, is a maintenance hangar at the end of a taxiway considered part of the aerodrome?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"No, maintenance hangars are considered part of the aerodrome operational area, but not the aerodrome.",
    "correctAnswer":"Yes, the definition of aerodrome includes any buildings adjacent to the area used in connection with the aerodrome.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(d)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:32:46.193168",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Yes, but only because the taxiway leads directly to the hangar.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"No, maintenance hangars are specifically excluded in the AIP GEN definition of \"aerodrome\"."
  },
  { 
    "id":"794e0541-56d4-4a7c-b7c0-7c7e97e40c91",
    "question": "The METAR AUTO \"21009KT 9999 OVC021/// 09/06\" indicates that;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"visibility is not reported due to a faulty sensor",
    "correctAnswer":"the cloud type (TCU or CB) cannot be determined",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:11:46.983405",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the sensor is faulty and is unable to detect the cloud type",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"cloud type is not reported if the cloud is reported as overcast"
  },
  { 
    "id":"89cf57f5-fc7e-4d52-9fcf-b87787723e25",
    "question": "The High Frequency (HF) band is commonly used",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"for short distance communication",
    "correctAnswer":"for long distance communication",
    "syllabusReference":"2.2.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 09:14:32.762022",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"in turboprop aircraft",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"as a backup to VHF communication"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6157bfe5-f694-44db-afdb-98f1aee2a530",
    "question": " The air that is warmed through contact with the earth's surface is warmed by;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"convection",
    "correctAnswer":"conduction",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:33:11.548137",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"insolation",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"albedo"
  },
  { 
    "id":"39ed2921-0361-4512-ad21-cf7f609119fb",
    "question": "  By definition, fog is reported when there is cloud on the surface and the visibility is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"more than 1000 metres but less than 8000 metres",
    "correctAnswer":"less than 1000 metres",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:17:17.671389",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"less than 5000 metres",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"1000 metres or more but less than 5000 metres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a8a3d26a-112b-4cf0-8239-34099927d9f5",
    "question": "How should the time 8:03am be transmitted when using an aviation radio?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"eight zero three a-m",
    "correctAnswer":"zero eight zero three",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(c)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:32:33.575670",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"zero three a-m",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"zero three a-m U-T-C"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0f8469db-82a2-46c3-9d4f-446637a6c713",
    "question": "When the temperature remains constant throughout a layer or air, despite an increase in height, this layer is termed;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"noctilucent",
    "correctAnswer":"isothermal",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:30:15.325951",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"isobaric",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"an inversion"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e9484aa4-365f-40dd-8277-70eb8a090422",
    "question": "In respect of Control Zones (CTR) and Control Areas (CTA);",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a CTA must not be lower than 500 feet AGL",
    "correctAnswer":"a CTR extends updwards from the surface of the earth/sea and can be class C or D airspace",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:43:41.169351",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a CTA extends updwards from the surface of the earth/sea and can be class C or D airspace",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a CTR must not be lower than 500 feet AGL"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2ee105f2-70da-4f41-8e73-5be6b4c76a58",
    "question": "What is the correct term to use in a radio transmission meaning \"yes\"?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Wilco",
    "correctAnswer":"Affirm",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:28:36.548261",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Roger",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Yes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8ef0cad1-06a8-445f-8296-e6e22f27b84b",
    "question": " Which combination of characteristics will typically cause the fastest accretion of aircraft icing?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Bunt edges of aircraft parts, high cloud water content, slower airspeed",
    "correctAnswer":"Sharp edges of aircraft parts, high cloud water content, faster airspeed",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:18:37.721241",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Sharp edges of aircraft parts, low cloud water content, faster airspeed",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Sharp edges of aircraft parts, high cloud water content, slower airspeed"
  },
  { 
    "id":"83e26672-38ec-4883-90a9-1c4567f0f639",
    "question": "A distance of 4.5 nautical miles is most accurately equal to which of the following distances?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"6 statute miles",
    "correctAnswer":"8.3 kilometres",
    "syllabusReference":"6.6.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:53:28.433777",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"3.9 statute miles",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2.4 kilometres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"183208c4-369a-4192-8d41-4708b6583983",
    "question": "The primary radio frequency for communicating with Napier control tower is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"119.1",
    "correctAnswer":"124.8",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:05:33.557733",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"109.9",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"125.6"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fab305e4-449b-4962-bd7d-c4f0c2a34717",
    "question": "At your present position, magnetic variation is 23 degrees East. Assuming on a nil wind day, and with nil deviation, you want to track 300 degrees True. What magnetic direction should you head?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"323 degrees",
    "correctAnswer":"277 degrees",
    "syllabusReference":"6.4.8",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:42:25.142084",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"300 degrees",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"023 degrees"
  },
  { 
    "id":"80726bb0-b8e1-425e-8601-e0edf75b0c92",
    "question": "ATC instructions you to \"SQUAWK IDENT\". Which transponder function should you activate?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Press the ALT button.",
    "correctAnswer":"Press the IDENT button.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 08:51:51.339611",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Change the transponder mode to SQUAWK.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Reset the transponder by setting it to STBY then back to ALT."
  },
  { 
    "id":"82d94666-91c6-469e-a180-c09a939edb0b",
    "question": "Climbing through the transition altitude, you should set your altimeter to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"QFE",
    "correctAnswer":"QNE",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:28:03.956660",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"QNH",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"QNF"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6d998e64-35e8-4fd6-981a-8d71598b0b66",
    "question": "You're taxing at a controlled aerodrome and notice your radio has stopped working. You see a series of white flashes coming from the tower. What does this mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Danger, be on the alert",
    "correctAnswer":"Return to starting point on aerodrome",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:53:13.249420",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Stop",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Cleared for take-off"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f0f60c2a-60b6-46e2-bdc2-a60df42eb488",
    "question": "After donating blood, a pilot should wait how long before flying?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"96 hours",
    "correctAnswer":"24 hours",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:44:06.252941",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"48 hours",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"12 hours"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fdafd273-81e8-4804-a197-f679dfaf5daa",
    "question": "You are flying from Hokitika to Christchurch when there is a significant disruption to ATC services and communication on the normal and expected radio frequencies is lost. TIBA is initiated. Which frequency should you now tune your radio to?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"119.65",
    "correctAnswer":"120.9",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:38:55.389810",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"127.2",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"118.4"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fa6f9984-0267-4c70-a66e-068d6bcbc158",
    "question": "Which of these is part of the definition for \"aerobatic flight\"?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"An intentional manoevre in which the aircraft sustains +4 'g' or -2 'g'.",
    "correctAnswer":"An intentional manoeuvre in which the aircraft is in sustained inverted flight or is rolled from upright to inverted or from inverted to upright position.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(c)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:22:20.614721",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"An intentional manoeuvre in which the aircraft is rolled beyond 60° angle of bank.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"An intentional manoeuvre in which the aircraft is in sustained inverted flight or is rolled beyond 60° angle of bank."
  },
  { 
    "id":"f5338d7d-15f8-459a-b11b-d584e4bbfd73",
    "question": " A katabatic wind;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"is a down slope wind that develops from mid morning",
    "correctAnswer":"is a down slope wind that develops from the early evening",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:52:44.964206",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"is a up slope wind that develops from the early evening",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"is an up slope wind that develops from mid morning"
  },
  { 
    "id":"8c8032a7-4305-4309-9d69-e942bad0540d",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"it will be automatically cancelled by the Rescue Coordination Centre",
    "correctAnswer":"you must cancel it via ATC, the internet or by phone",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 09:57:28.572538",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"there is no need to cancel it as you were cleared for a full stop landing by ATC",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"you must cancel the flight plan but for security purposes, this can only be completed via the same method as the filing method",
    "question": "You file a VFR flight plan and pilot an aircraft from Christchurch to Dunedin. ATC clears you to land and taxi clear. The entire flight has been uneventful. In terms of your flight plan;"
  },
  { 
    "id":"47c54828-2760-4156-91ef-773909a6e8b4",
    "question": "  An anabatic wind",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"is an up slope wind that develops from the early evening",
    "correctAnswer":"is an upslope wind that develops from mid morning",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:19:22.281512",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"is a down slope wind that develops from the early evening",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"is a down slope wind that develops from mid morning"
  },
  { 
    "id":"27ea7f4e-5068-43f4-9004-d86c259ec018",
    "question": "In the following TAF, issued in November, what surface wind can be expected at NZWF if the arrival time was 2000 hrs NZDT? \"TAF AMD NZWF 100437Z 1004/1011 VRB02KT 20KM -RA FEW030 BKN050 FM100600 14012KT 20KM -RA BKN030 2000FT WIND 34020KT BECMG 1005/1007 16020KT =\"",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"340 degrees True at 20 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"140 degrees True at 12 knots",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:24:08.208765",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Variable at 2 knots",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"160 degrees True at 20 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b5e1df2e-a8c3-4bf7-9e66-98f0e14ebb0a",
    "question": "The ambient temperature at 14 000 feet AMSL is -8℃. What is the ISA temperature at 14 000 feet?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"ISA -2℃",
    "correctAnswer":"ISA +5℃",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:55:12.498013",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"ISA +9℃",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"ISA +20℃"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6226b469-9797-4615-bd6f-86296d8d11e8",
    "question": "You are flying at an indicated airspeed of 95 knots when your passenger, who is unfamiliar with the term 'knot', asks you how fast that is. An accurate reply would be;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a knot has no equivalent to ground speed so the answer is always going to be 95 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"175 kilometres per hour",
    "syllabusReference":"6.8.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:54:30.359019",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"110 nautical miles per hour",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"51 statute miles per hour"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9bf6d48f-bbff-4bf3-a31c-c6fb437e864f",
    "question": "What is the correct way to transmit a callsign for a Cessna Skyhawk, with tail number ZK-XYP?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Cessna Zulu Kilo",
    "correctAnswer":"Cardinal Xray-Yankee-Papa",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(i)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:16:14.638953",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Cessna Xray-Yankee-Piper",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Cessna Cardinal Zulu-Kilo-Xray-Yankee-Papa"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c3ea402e-153c-41f3-8ca8-4bc6bce73209",
    "question": " In respect of the friction layer;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the smoother the surface, the deeper the friction layer",
    "correctAnswer":"the rougher the surface, the deeper the friction layer",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:54:14.117142",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the stronger the wind, the shallower the friction layer",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the lighter the wind, the deeper the friction layer"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f47fff9d-789b-4b7a-ac54-80012c1e7fbe",
    "question": "  The term \"fitness to fly\" refers to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a pilot's physical fitness only",
    "correctAnswer":"a pilot's mental and physical fitness",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:01:34.236352",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"a pilot's ability as a pilot",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a pilot's mental fitness only"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5da9af63-7e41-4fd1-a097-09abd4296fa3",
    "question": " In New Zealand, 13 000 feet AMSL is known as the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"transition level",
    "correctAnswer":"transition altitude",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:44:58.569926",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"pressure altitude",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"pressure level"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9a55f933-46bb-4163-89f8-27969ab9f0c8",
    "question": " TREND forecasts are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"valid for four hours following their issue and take precedence over the TAF for this period",
    "correctAnswer":"valid for two hours following their issue and take precedence over the TAF for this period",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:40:10.191139",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"valid for two hours following their issue but do not take precedence over the TAF for this period",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"valid for four hours following their issue but do not take precedence over the TAF for this period"
  },
  { 
    "id":"7e8a7560-5b47-4e02-a7e9-db479ecbe324",
    "question": "The 'Oxygen paradox' refers to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"symptoms of hypoxia will worsen if the Oxygen given is 'stale'",
    "correctAnswer":"symptoms of hypoxia may momentarily worsen when first going onto Oxygen, but this will pass quickly",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:57:51.175312",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"if Oxygen is self administered, hypoxic symptoms will initially worsen whereas this will not occur if Oxygen is administered by another crew member",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"giving Oxygen to a hypoxic person will worsen their condition unless given along with treatment in a hyperbaric chamber"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a01cd5fa-363f-494f-81b0-f544456e821e",
    "question": "What is the correct pronunciation of \"3\" in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Three",
    "correctAnswer":"Tree",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2.(c)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:16:55.121340",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Thrie",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Free"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1a482bf2-a17d-41b6-8a19-3e88bbe25812",
    "question": "You are enroute to land at Dunedin airport and, having obtained a clearance, have entered the control zone.  As you approach downwind your radio stops working. You notice that the control tower is shining a steady red light at you. What does this mean?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Leave the control zone without delay",
    "correctAnswer":"Give way to other traffic and continue in the circuit",
    "syllabusReference":"2.16.10",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:41:55.111575",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Aerodrome unsafe - Do not land",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Danger - be on the alert"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fc69b037-a8a3-4d33-a3d2-9f968ae4987f",
    "question": " May a pilot in command of an aircraft performing a Commercial Transport Operation (CTO) perform deliberate manoeuvres below 500 feet AGL?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Yes, if they notify CAA in advance and the manoeuvres are not within 150m of a built up area",
    "correctAnswer":"Yes, if they plan with and brief every person and organisation involved, and take reasonable care not to create a hazard",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:52:35.198040",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Yes, if they have the approval of the land owners prior to flying",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"No. Flight below 500 feet AGL is prohibited as part of a CTO"
  },
  { 
    "id":"565b500c-ab2f-4ccb-a3e4-6a092bef7ee4",
    "question": "An Automatic Weather Information Broadcast (AWIB);",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"is a more accurate and reliable source of weather information than a more simplistic Automatic Weather Station",
    "correctAnswer":"may contain information that is from non-certified sources",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:36:34.384209",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"is similar to an Automatic Weather Station except it has runway in use and traffic advisory functions",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"is operated and maintained by MetService at non-attended aerodromes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"82e7c507-7272-4c41-b1f8-b4914c76fcb4",
    "question": "With respect to conventional aeroplane controls;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the rudder controls an aircraft about the normal axis and the elevators about the longitudinal axis",
    "correctAnswer":"the ailerons control an aircraft about the longitudinal axis and the rudder about the normal axis",
    "syllabusReference":"12.58.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:38:31.701691",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the elevators controls an aircraft about the longitudinal axis and the rudder about the normal axis",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the rudder controls an aircraft about the lateral axis and the ailerons about the longitudinal axis"
  },
  { 
    "id":"230cd143-ea46-4098-bb15-1690b894e49a",
    "question": "Major sources of adding water vapour to the atmosphere are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"water vapour being in a 'closed cell' and recycled via the Walker and Hadley cells",
    "correctAnswer":"evaporation from water sources on earth, including sublimination from ice surfaces",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:16:18.469140",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"convection of moisture from the land surfaces, including the lifting of fog and evaporation of dew",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"rain evaporating as it falls to earth"
  },
  { 
    "id":"30a1d387-9f7c-4cba-ba5a-bb093cb10edf",
    "question": " The eyes account for approximately how much information about body orientation received by the brain?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"40 %",
    "correctAnswer":"80 %",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:42:52.712458",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"60 %",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"70 %"
  },
  { 
    "id":"16b468dd-f525-43b5-96d3-da75e4c6efa7",
    "question": "An aircraft is exempt from carrying an ELT if it is being ferried to a place where one can be installed and;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the flight is able to be tracked by radar at all times",
    "correctAnswer":"no passengers are carried",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:01:54.213975",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"contact can be made at all times with an ATS unit via radio",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a flight plan is filed, or other flight following arrangements are made"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bc71aba4-8916-48e3-a607-32351c571d5d",
    "question": "A control tower issues you an instruction to \"Track direct to the racecourse.\"  You are unable to do so without entering cloud. What should you do?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Transmit: \"Track direct to the racecourse due cloud.\"",
    "correctAnswer":"Transmit: \"Unable to track direct to the racecourse due cloud.\"",
    "syllabusReference":"2.12.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:36:13.166369",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Transmit: \"Track direct to the racecourse not available.\"",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Transmit: \"Wilco.\""
  },
  { 
    "id":"2ee6225c-7167-41cb-a9ed-e600e726837d",
    "question": " When may a person take dangerous goods aboard an aircraft as carry on baggage?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"never",
    "correctAnswer":"when permitted by the technical instructions",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:46:37.091246",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"when the Director of CAA is notified at least 24 hours prior to the intended departure time",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"when the pilot in command gives approval"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d9688932-6c35-4592-9849-506217dbf6dd",
    "question": "The 'O' in the decision making model FDODAR, stands for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"continue with Operations",
    "correctAnswer":"consider Options",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:14:51.048277",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"use an Organisation's procedures",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"be careful of Overload"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e08e2fa8-d09a-439d-999c-d2da1a19e402",
    "question": "When flying over a layer of mist or haze, it is better to fly higher than it is to fly just above the mist or haze as this;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"reduces the chances of ice accretion",
    "correctAnswer":"increases the horizontal visibility as penetration range is still the same",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:18:12.711073",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"reduces the amount of mist or haze to look through, thus enabling greater horizontal visibility",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"ensures a faster ground speed"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f3d87bfc-d3a9-4788-bea0-c42824aa97d9",
    "question": " Aside from a certificate of airworthiness and radio station equipment approval levels, what documents is it mandatory for each New Zealand registered aircraft operating in New Zealand to carry?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Registration certificate, normal and emergency checklists, and a VNC covering the area to be flown",
    "correctAnswer":"Flight manual, technical log, and weight and balance data",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:01:17.619384",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Flight manual, registration certificate, and load sheet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Normal and emergency checklists, load sheet and technical log"
  },
  { 
    "id":"edf72205-70f7-4b7a-a624-afe90b3c254d",
    "question": " Hypoxia is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"caused by the bends",
    "correctAnswer":"the lower than normal concentration of Oxygen in arterial blood",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:38:21.250315",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the absence of Oxygen in arterial blood",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"caused by a shortness of breath and rapid breathing"
  },
  { 
    "id":"55fcff2a-ce9e-4e56-b54b-c78712a0a060",
    "question": "If your microphone was broken in flight but you could still hear and transmit, how would you answer \"Yes\" to a question asked by an ATS unit?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Activate the transmitter twice",
    "correctAnswer":"Activate the transmitter once",
    "syllabusReference":"2.16.8",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:39:45.864557",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Activate the transmitter three times",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Activate the transmitter four times"
  },
  { 
    "id":"521dc883-4cf2-4169-9844-8738bfcb8ff6",
    "question": "You're ferrying an aircraft with an inoperative ELT to an airport where it can be repaired. What restriction applies?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The flight must not be over mountainous terrain.",
    "correctAnswer":"You can't take any passengers.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.8.4",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 02:29:43.740478",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The departure and destination airfields must be within 50 nm of each other.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The aircraft must not have more than 4 seats."
  },
  { 
    "id":"54fe2c96-7c6a-437e-817b-5837c2fd2f1c",
    "question": "Rotor zones may be found;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"above the stable air layer on the lee side of a mountain, when there is a mountain wave development",
    "correctAnswer":"below the stable air layer on the lee side of a mountain, when there is a mountain wave development",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:23:43.911146",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"above the stable air layer when there is an inversion on the lee side of a mountain",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"below the stable air layer when there is an inversion on the lee side of a mountain"
  },
  { 
    "id":"2ffe2313-eac6-4ab8-ab08-b2dd2361c55f",
    "question": "In an aircraft where occupants are wearing headsets with boom microphones, activating the Push To Talk (PTT) button",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"will transmit the microphone signals from all occupants",
    "correctAnswer":"will transmit only the microphone signal of the person in the same seating position as the PTT being pressed",
    "syllabusReference":"2.4.4(a)",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 09:59:14.741822",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"allows occupants of the aircraft to hear each other through their headsets",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"transmits microphone signals from only occupants in the front seats"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b033a866-e201-4a96-835e-831ef34fef7e",
    "question": "How should the letter \"H\" be said in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Aych",
    "correctAnswer":"Hotel",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:12:00.484015",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Henry",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Hornet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"32162798-4c3d-4244-8e43-5ba85939619e",
    "question": "What does Readability Three mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Unreadable.",
    "correctAnswer":"Readable, but with difficulty.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(m)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:43:12.295600",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Readable now and then.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Readable."
  },
  { 
    "id":"1b17194b-3729-4e96-baa6-aed4e7ea1be0",
    "question": "When operating in Class A airspace...",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Two-way communications are required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace, unless flying on an IFR flight plan.",
    "correctAnswer":"Two-way communications are required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace, unless authorised.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(c)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:32:15.543820",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Two-way communications are always required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Two-way communications are required with the ATC unit responsible for the airspace, unless flying an aircraft equipped with dual ADSB transmitters."
  },
  { 
    "id":"c17c6281-7f90-4710-9400-04ddbd1b9772",
    "question": "If someone suffers from chronic fatigue;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"this should be cured by two consecutive good nights of sleep",
    "correctAnswer":"medical help will normally be required to assist in recovery from it",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:54:51.316592",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"this will have a sudden onset",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"it should not affect performance when piloting a flight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"46f81af9-64ee-466c-9876-2c64c73ca833",
    "question": "During a cross country flight test you notice that after 30 nm from your origin, you are 4 nm to the left of your intended track. What is your track error?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"8 degrees right",
    "correctAnswer":"8 degrees left",
    "syllabusReference":"6.36.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:56:59.992786",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"4 degrees left",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"4 degrees right"
  },
  { 
    "id":"4d622595-1381-4139-ab2c-ffe4dfb38f81",
    "question": "  The Australian wet monsoon season;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"takes affect in July, and peaks in September",
    "correctAnswer":"takes affect in December and peaks in February",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:18:58.341196",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"takes affect in September, and peaks in November",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"takes affect in February, and peaks in April"
  },
  { 
    "id":"72f5ad59-85fa-4560-af35-52e15dbbde1a",
    "question": "A 12 month competency check, required by a Part 135 operation, is deemed to have been carried out on the due date if it is completed up to how many days in advance of the due date?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"30 days in advance",
    "correctAnswer":"60 days in advance",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:39:50.388582",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"no days in advance. The new due date runs 12 months from the completion date",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"7 days in advance"
  },
  { 
    "id":"954b5bc0-d82f-418a-9fbb-d8fb7a3aa8b4",
    "question": " The altitude that a correctly functioning altimeter will read when 1013.25 is set on the subscale is the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"density altitude",
    "correctAnswer":"pressure altitude",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:20:54.764161",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"QFE",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"conditional altitude"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f611eb22-e01b-4480-be33-855ed10f85e2",
    "question": "Instruments which rely on static air pressure to operate correctly are the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"vertical speed indicator and turn coordinator",
    "correctAnswer":"altimeter and air speed indicator",
    "syllabusReference":"12.36.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:37:25.217072",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"vertical speed indicator and artificial horizon",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"air speed indicator and directional indicator"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ad520bca-d626-4f5d-a7f1-f5ebe8f834ce",
    "authorName":""
    ,"addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:27:21.109277","examId":"ppl-3",
    "question": "The majority of General Aviation aircraft use a",
    "syllabusReference":"2.2.2(c)",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"High Frequency (HF) radio, which has better clarity than a Very High Frequency (VHF) radio",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Low Frequency (LF) radio, which has better clarity than a High Frequency (HF) radio",
    "correctAnswer":"Very High Frequency (VHF) radio, which has better clarity than a High Frequency (HF) radio",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Very Low Frequency (VLF) radio, which has better clarity than a Very High Frequency (VHF) radio"
  },
  { 
    "id":"94d835f0-8686-4766-b99d-d7458f957195",
    "question": "On a particular leg of a cross country flight you calculate that your TAS is 110 knots and your GS is 90 knots.  If your aircraft uses 36 litres of fuel per hour and the leg is 135 nm long, how much fuel will you expect to use on that leg?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"44 litres",
    "correctAnswer":"54 litres",
    "syllabusReference":"6.46.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 19:00:15.932177",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"51 litres",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"49 litres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"283536fc-f1fc-4f12-8b47-8603f82dc76b",
    "question": "The angle of attack is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the resultant angle between the chord line of the wing and the angle of incidence",
    "correctAnswer":"the angle between the relative airflow and the chord line of the wing",
    "syllabusReference":"12.6.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:35:10.357510",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the angle of incidence and the airflow",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the angle between the horizontal and the chord line of the wing"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6b5b922e-62b2-4a8b-b482-cea975849e2b",
    "question": " As the wind speed increases, Coriolis force;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"decreases",
    "correctAnswer":"increases",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:19:19.311566",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"remains the same",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"decreases until the wind is below about 5 knots, then remains constant"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e1d25741-2193-459a-a556-cf8c81ef8e69",
    "question": "An aircraft flying above the freezing level descends into warm, moist air on approach to an airport. There is no cloud. What is likely to be experienced?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Rime ice",
    "correctAnswer":"Hoar frost",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:53:28.857162",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Clear ice",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Mixed ice"
  },
  { 
    "id":"107ec2fc-f15f-40a1-baf1-a05a366f4398",
    "question": "At an aerodrome situated at 2000 feet AMSL, the QNH is 1000 hPa.  What is the pressure altitude?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1610 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"2390 feet",
    "syllabusReference":"12.100.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:39:57.715844",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"3000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2610 feet"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a84834d3-10b1-4fe7-8cc3-d9c4aaac5f6d",
    "question": " In class C controlled airspace;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"VFR flights are not separated from other VFR flights during the night, but are separated during the day",
    "correctAnswer":"VFR flights are not separated from other VFR flights both day and night",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:07:29.998390",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"VFR flights are not separated from other VFR flights during the day, but are separated at night",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"VFR flights are separated from other VFR flights day and night"
  },
  { 
    "id":"bf887545-43a3-44c5-a5a9-ecc237e16ee9",
    "question": "What is the correct phrase to use if you are unable to understand all or part of a transmission and would like the sender to repeat it?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Please repeat.",
    "correctAnswer":"Say again.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(d)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-13 21:38:13.169250",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Unable to understand, repeat.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"I read you 2."
  },
  { 
    "id":"b1f3e869-096f-4451-8673-a926a509178e",
    "question": "In rotor streaming conditions, severe turbulence may be found where the rotor is the strongest, which is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"in the lee of the moutain range, at a height equal to approximately two times the wavelength of the mountain wave",
    "correctAnswer":"in the lee of a mountain range, at or just below ridge height",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:22:40.296430",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"in the lee of a mountain range, within approximately 1000 feet above the top of the ridge",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"on the windward side of a mountain range, below the top of the mountain range"
  },
  { 
    "id":"46caa7c7-17b1-47a0-b116-e1d999dbb984",
    "question": " As people get older they suffer hearing loss, with hearing becoming less acute particularly with;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"hearing sounds from behind",
    "correctAnswer":"the high frequency range",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:41:32.351557",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"hearing sounds from in front",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the low frequency range"
  },
  { 
    "id":"782fa5a6-aa73-4fec-a490-b11051a5365d",
    "question": "Oxygen enters the bloodstream via the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"diaphragm",
    "correctAnswer":"alveoli",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:41:07.151594",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"pulmonary artery",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"stipules"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a82ba33b-deef-4418-a56a-32e5e6c503b1",
    "question": "Your True course is 310 degrees, you have a True Air Speed (TAS) of 120 knots, and the wind is 180 degrees True at 16 knots. What will your True heading and ground speed be? ",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Heading 186 degrees, Ground speed 130 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"Heading 304 degrees, Ground speed 130 knots",
    "syllabusReference":"6.34.4(a) & (b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:56:39.832863",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Heading 305 degrees, Ground speed 120 knots",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Heading 184 degrees, Ground speed 128 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"6163f3ba-1078-4108-aaa2-a42a241bcf7a",
    "question": "An automatic broadcast of aerodrome and weather information provided specifically for the facilitation of aviation is better known as a/an;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"TAF",
    "correctAnswer":"AWIB",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:08:07.520819",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"BWR",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"ATIS"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ef209a73-b3d1-41ee-b14d-95bccaa454d8",
    "question": "What is the minimum separation that will be applied by ATC for a light aircraft departing immediately after a heavy aircraft, off the same runway direction and from the same take-off position?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"3 minutes",
    "correctAnswer":"2 minutes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:56:31.485973",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"4 minutes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"5 minutes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9167f7a4-2fdb-4147-9cdf-284484381ff0",
    "question": "Under what conditions are you allowed to enter controlled airspace without an operable transponder?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"If maintaining visual flight rules.",
    "correctAnswer":"With ATC approval.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.12",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 01:54:06.526184",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Never. An operable transponder is always required in controlled airspace.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Any time when flying below 10,000 AMSL."
  },
  { 
    "id":"dd418926-9b51-4ef8-8b8a-246c701a5c08",
    "question": "You are flying towards Rangiora aerodrome and hear an aircraft report that they are taking off from Rangiora and will be carrying out manoeuvres within the \"vicinity of the aerodrome.\" If that pilot is using the term correctly, they are intending to operate;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"within the aerodrome traffic circuit",
    "correctAnswer":"not more than 10 nm laterally from Rangiora airfield",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:06:12.838821",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"no specified distance from the aerodrome but are intending to re-enter the Rangiora circuit without further warning",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"not more than 15 nm laterally from Rangiora airfield"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e603f2c9-41ed-4a95-9a10-1506be412a52",
    "question": "While flying you want to talk to a control tower but discover there is no reception on the frequency your radio is tuned to. You have checked you have the correct frequency set. What should you do next?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Squawk ident",
    "correctAnswer":"Check the squelch level",
    "syllabusReference":"2.4.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:29:40.851964",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Change from VHF to HF for that frequency",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Tune the radio to the local VOR frequency"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0e6994e0-e352-4c7c-8126-a740f9a8270a",
    "question": "  Which of the following are the minimum instrument requirements for a day VFR flight? A means of indicating;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"direction, oil pressure and turn",
    "correctAnswer":"airspeed, direction and time",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:33:35.644699",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"rate of vertical speed, pitch and direction",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"oil temperature, time and pitch"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b9eb3bb7-11d0-4cda-936f-10ab2ab5eb3e",
    "question": "The purpose of an Aerodrome Frequency Response Unit (AFRU) is to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"advise pilots of the correct frequency to use when flying to aerodromes where there is no ATS unit, or no ATS unit on duty",
    "correctAnswer":"confirm to pilots that they are transmitting on the correct frequency and that their radio is working",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:34:39.590262",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"provide maintenance staff with notification of 'frequency drift' by ground based radio equipment",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"advise aircraft and ground stations if two, or more, stations have transmitted at the same time"
  },
  { 
    "id":"034c55d9-2a64-4455-8142-0fe0366531d6",
    "question": "What information will a transponder transmit transmitting in Mode C?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Identification (squawk code) and position.",
    "correctAnswer":"Identification (squawk code), position, and altitude.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 02:46:21.586866",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Identification (squawk code) and altitude only.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"None, Mode C is only used for TCAS alerts."
  },
  { 
    "id":"f053e42b-a68b-4a7b-8560-dc5ec7cf6d1c",
    "question": "What information will a transponder transmit transmitting in Mode A?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Identification (squawk code), position, and altitude.",
    "correctAnswer":"Identification (squawk code) and position.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.4(a)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 02:44:28.703669",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Identification (squawk code), position, and IDENT.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"IDENT and altitude."
  },
  { 
    "id":"a6a681c8-b567-497a-9e00-c76a94d674e4",
    "question": "Relief is indicated on a New Zealand aeronautical chart by means of;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"shading and contour lines",
    "correctAnswer":"colour and spot heights",
    "syllabusReference":"6.26.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:51:48.473828",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"shading, contour lines and spot heights",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Heights of towns above mean sea level (AMSL)"
  },
  { 
    "id":"42a49347-23c3-4172-b53a-644fe322c2f8",
    "question": "Your aircraft consumes 30 litres of avgas per hour, and you plan on a 3 hour flight. Including the mandatory minimum of 30 minutes fuel you must carry, what is the weight of the minimum fuel you must carry for the flight?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"65 kg",
    "correctAnswer":"76 kg",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.18(f)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:47:01.194100",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"90 kg",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"55 kg"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a21bcf8c-054a-4bd9-bab3-0d2518da611c",
    "question": "The horizontal component of the Coriolis force equation is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"2vsinΦ",
    "correctAnswer":"2𝛀vsinΦ",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:23:19.047304",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"2𝝿vsinΦ",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"2𝝿rsinvΦ"
  },
  { 
    "id":"5ce1e136-bc12-4231-8c05-5b360748787d",
    "question": "35 US gallons is equal to;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"177 litres",
    "correctAnswer":"132 litres",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.18(e)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:48:46.680764",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"203 litres",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"335 litres"
  },
  { 
    "id":"488fa1ca-c362-488c-b316-c5623055f2a7",
    "question": "You are cruising at an altitude of 8,500 feet and the outside air temperature at that altitude is 0 degrees Celsius. Your IAS is 90 knots. What is your TAS? Disregard any instrument errors.",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"79 knots",
    "correctAnswer":"103 knots",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.2",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:58:00.152590",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"88 knots",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"96 knots"
  },
  { 
    "id":"057bf78f-c378-4ec9-a29b-3f8360f64391",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a loss of communications",
    "correctAnswer":"a hijacking",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.6",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:31:08.174469",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"an emergency situation, such as an engine failure",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"an urgency situation, which does not involve immediate danger to those in the air or on the ground",
    "question": "A transponder code of 7500 indicates"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a430b82b-152a-4be4-9087-b6c30250d166",
    "question": "  The wavelength of a mountain wave is significantly influenced by;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the height of the mountains and the amplitude of the mountain wave",
    "correctAnswer":"the strength of the wind and the shape of the lee mountain slope",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:15:53.549323",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the strength of the wind and the width of the mountains",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the strength of the wind and the shape of the upwind mountain slope"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e278c865-6a78-475a-98b6-a31d66e56a76",
    "question": " TREND forecasts are;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"valid for four hours following their issue and take precedence over the TAF for this period",
    "correctAnswer":"valid for two hours following their issue and take precedence over the TAF for this period",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:08:18.643948",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"valid for four hours following their issue but do not take precedence over the TAF for this period",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"valid for two hours following their issue but do not take precedence over the TAF for this period"
  },
  { 
    "id":"87f5af25-bc93-4708-a4f6-ca264584e331",
    "question": " \"Autokinesis\" is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"during times of low workload, a pilot may feel like they are outside the aircraft looking in",
    "correctAnswer":"in an otherwise darkened visual field, a single stationary light appears to wander",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:00:29.820533",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"when there is a loss of depth perception, caused by a solid layer of overcast or snow covered terrain",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"when a bright light is interrupted by a moving object such as a propeller"
  },
  { 
    "id":"b9b5a341-1910-4bfb-ad92-5b17cfa107f9",
    "question": "Rod cells in the eye;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"cannot perceive colour but can perceive detail",
    "correctAnswer":"cannot perceive colour or detail",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:05:27.281870",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"can perceive colour but cannot perceive detail",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"can perceive both colour and detail"
  },
  { 
    "id":"81763d78-4a53-48a7-9134-5f762020fb1f",
    "question": "A transponder code of 7600 indicates",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an emergency situation, such as an engine failure",
    "correctAnswer":"a loss of communications",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.6",
    "addedDate":"2022-06-26 10:18:31.118954",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"an urgency situation, which does not involve immediate danger to those in the air or on the ground",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a hijacking"
  },
  { 
    "id":"04b91a42-bac3-4585-b813-7f303629f938",
    "question": " Autokinesis can occur;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"when a bright light is interrupted by a moving object such as a propeller",
    "correctAnswer":"in an otherwise darkened visual field, a single stationary light appears to wander",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:45:31.413319",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"when there is a loss of depth perception, caused by a solid layer of overcast or snow covered terrain",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"during times of low workload, a pilot may feel like they are outside the aircraft looking in"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d687635a-ff2f-4757-944f-503efa39ecc2",
    "question": "To avoid a collision or near miss, aircraft approaching head on shall;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"both alter course to the left",
    "correctAnswer":"both alter course to the right",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:03:53.135159",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the aircraft on a northerly magnetic heading shall climb slightly, while the aircraft on a southerly heading shall descend slightly",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"both alter course so that they keep the other aircraft on their right"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f0c3c33c-1dbf-49a9-8380-6664faeb53b3",
    "question": "The eyes account for approximately how much information about body orientation received by the brain?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"40 %",
    "correctAnswer":"80 %",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:56:02.276744",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"60 %",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"70 %"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9f4e8fe5-7a5c-4b07-8976-be1ee56f4992",
    "question": "Propellers have a blade, or helical, twist as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-2",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"if the blade did not have a twist in it, the inner sections of blade at the hub would be operated at an angle of attack above the stalling angle",
    "correctAnswer":"if the blade angle was the same along the length of each blade, the angle of attack would continuously increase toward the tip",
    "syllabusReference":"12.72.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:39:36.716395",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"an increase in blade angle of attack is needed as the blade nears the tip",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the rotational velocity of the blade reduces as it nears the tip"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d14389e3-f976-4282-b797-db9bae00bef1",
    "question": " If there is a simultaneous stimulation of two of the semi-circular canals, the illusion that may result is known as the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the leans",
    "correctAnswer":"cross coupled turning (coriolis) effect",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:00:59.716090",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"somatogravic illusion",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"somatogyral illusion"
  },
  { 
    "id":"16e6cb6f-d645-4ec3-90b0-402353980047",
    "question": "  The time of useful consciousness without Oxygen at 18000 feet is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"30 to 45 minutes",
    "correctAnswer":"15 to 30 minutes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:19:42.089766",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"3 to 5 minutes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"15 to 30 seconds"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3d34cce5-7429-4c18-8a2f-42d3ab5a53a2",
    "question": "Rime ice is formed;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"when an aircraft descends from above the freezing level into warm, moist air",
    "correctAnswer":"when small super cooled water droplets at between -20℃ and -40℃ come into contact with an aircraft, and freezes almost instantaneously on an aircraft",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:45:28.910621",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"between temperatures of -3℃ and -12℃. Freezing is delayed on contact with the aircraft and part of the droplet flows back",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"when large super cooled droplets fall onto a warmer aircraft skin, causing freezing to be delayed"
  },
  { 
    "id":"dd5125e2-fd01-4b42-aa98-69764053a27f",
    "question": "What information is contained in the AIP supplement?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Permanent changes to the information contained in the AIPNZ that are published by means of special pages.",
    "correctAnswer":"Temporary changes to the information contained in the AIPNZ that are published by means of special pages.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.4(j)",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-10 09:46:58.164666",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Temporary changes to the information contained in the AIPNZ that are published as regular pages during the AIP update cycle.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Permanent changes to the information contained in the AIPNZ that are published as regular pages during the AIP update cycle."
  },
  { 
    "id":"aa4250e4-1746-4f2a-af0d-0769d753ac96",
    "question": "You are flying to an airfield for the first time, where the runway is wider than that of the airfield you usually fly at. For which sort of illusion should you most likely be on guard?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The approach to land may seem too shallow",
    "correctAnswer":"The runway may give the illusion of you being closer than you are, and you may level off too early",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:39:46.335719",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The approach to land may seem too steep",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The runway may give the illusion of you being higher than you are, and you may not level off early enough"
  },
  { 
    "id":"fbd5c29a-d822-40e6-ba94-3b3e517e98e5",
    "question": "Which of these is required to hold an aviation document, according to the Civil Aviation Act 1990?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Pilots and flight crew, but not air traffic or aviation security personnel.",
    "correctAnswer":"Aircraft, flight crew members, air traffic service personnel and air traffic services.",
    "syllabusReference":"4.2.2",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-09 03:36:08.197768",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Aircraft and services only. Aviation documents held by pilots and flight crew members are referred to as \"licenses\" and aren't part of the CA Act 1990.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Pilots, flight crew, air traffic service personnel, and other personnel only. Aviation documents for aircraft and services are referred to as \"registrations\" and aren't part of the CA Act 1990."
  },
  { 
    "id":"d7dd480f-7a4d-4bab-8ca8-15517f09199f",
    "question": "How should the letter \"U\" be said in a radio transmission?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Unicorn",
    "correctAnswer":"Uniform",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:13:19.772737",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Yu",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Union"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ca14e18f-a7bb-4573-b5e8-c22f190592fb",
    "question": "For rotor streaming to form requires;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"an unstable layer at about ridge top level, winds increasing with height, and wind direction close to perpendicular to a mountain range",
    "correctAnswer":"a stable layer at about ridge top level, winds increasing with height, and wind direction close to perpendicular to a mountain range",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:14:30.208767",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"an unstable layer at about ridge top level, winds decreasing with height, and wind direction close to parallel to a mountain range",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a stable layer at about ridge top level, winds decreasing with height, and wind direction close to perpendicular to a mountain range"
  },
  { 
    "id":"a457c976-2eae-4406-aa42-82f757a74d18",
    "question": "Your aircraft has used 237 litres of fuel in 3 hours and 15 minutes. What is the fuel consumption per hour?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"77 litres per hour",
    "correctAnswer":"73 litres per hour",
    "syllabusReference":"6.28.12",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:48:05.434713",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"94 litres per hour",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"82 litres per hour"
  },
  { 
    "id":"0ef30f76-95a2-48f0-b93f-80cbbb782470",
    "question": "An effective visual search technique involves;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"dividing the field of vision into four or five sectors and focusing on each sector for 20 seconds",
    "correctAnswer":"dividing the field of vision into 20 degree sectors and focusing on each sector for 2 seconds",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:15:43.928441",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"dividing the field of vision into a maximum of 20 slots which total the entire field of vision",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"maintaining constant eye movement across the entire field of vision"
  },
  { 
    "id":"17501de1-978e-45de-bb20-15be89d1e927",
    "question": "One of the requirements for the development of a thunderstorm is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a dry atmosphere",
    "correctAnswer":"an atmosphere that is unstable through a deep layer",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:37:51.395061",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the lack of any trigger action which would preempt an initial upsurge of air",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"a relationship with the equatorial trough"
  },
  { 
    "id":"245d3653-2a43-4a10-ab67-3d65ef40723b",
    "question": "  In New Zealand, if the QNH zone setting is 980 hPa or lower;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the transition altitude becomes 16 000 feet",
    "correctAnswer":"the transition level becomes FL160",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:12:12.239301",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the transition altitude becomes 13 000 feet",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the transition level becomes FL130"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f40a73e6-a47e-457d-9ac8-dd5c67976601",
    "question": "A UNICOM service is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"staffed by Airways staff at uncontrolled aerodromes",
    "correctAnswer":"staffed by non-Airways staff at uncontrolled aerodromes",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.6(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:35:05.343842",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"staffed by Airways staff at controlled aerodromes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"staffed by non-Airways staff at controlled aerodromes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"d89978db-89e6-4a9e-8b83-2d481e321443",
    "question": " In the SADIE decision making model, the D stands for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Discuss the problem with other crew",
    "correctAnswer":"Develop a solution",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:39:18.394642",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Decide on who should solve the problem",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Define the problem to be solved"
  },
  { 
    "id":"81eed877-4633-4a11-a4ca-aca671d20c1a",
    "question": "According to section 27C of the Civil Aviation Act 1990, when must an aviation licence holder notify the Director of Civil Aviation about a change in their medical condition?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"When they begin taking any prescription-only medication",
    "correctAnswer":"When they are aware of, or have reasonable grounds to suspect, any change in their medical condition that may interfere with the safe privileges of their licence",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:51:41.693502",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"When their doctor or medical examiner advises them that they no longer meet the medical standard of the medical certificate they hold",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"When they have received the results of a medical test, being a blood test or any other test, which shows a degradation of a previous medical condition"
  },
  { 
    "id":"40cde54e-c76b-40f6-8a89-29af741fab47",
    "question": "Regarding speed and velocity;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Speed is a vector, while velocity is a scalar",
    "correctAnswer":"Speed is a scalar, while velocity is a vector",
    "syllabusReference":"6.8.4",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:50:50.854013",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Both speed and velocity are vectors",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Both speed and velocity are scalars"
  },
  { 
    "id":"56ff8f9e-8630-440f-b792-0e755870f4ba",
    "question": " The partial pressure of Oxygen in the lungs at sea level is approximately;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"125 mmHg",
    "correctAnswer":"102 mmHg",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:07:25.945764",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"201 mmHg",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"150 mmHg"
  },
  { 
    "id":"ab2cfc8d-958e-48f7-b11e-aa1cb4a67d01",
    "question": "A MAYDAY call should be made if you encounter what sort of situation?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"You or someone else are in possible danger and require immediate assistance",
    "correctAnswer":"You or someone else are in imminent danger and require immediate assistance",
    "syllabusReference":"2.14.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:37:15.882109",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"You or someone else are in possible danger but do not require immediate assistance",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"You or someone else are in imminent danger but do not require immediate assistance"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e329ec0f-92c8-4110-ab6a-c8024bbf266d",
    "question": " Decompression sickness (\"the bends\") is caused by;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the partial pressure of Oxygen being less than that in the body and so allowing Oxygen to leach into the body's tissues, especially in the joints",
    "correctAnswer":"Nitrogen coming out of solution and into the body's tissues",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:03:19.354953",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Nitrogen being excreted from the body via gas exchange in the lungs",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Oxygen and Nitrogen displacing other gases within the blood stream and joints"
  },
  { 
    "id":"f6d7009d-3cf2-4829-a22f-ef8abebb746a",
    "question": "If ATC instructs you to \"SQUAWK ALTITUDE\", what should you do?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "syllabusReference":"2.6.8",
    "addedDate":"2022-07-02 09:27:13.735873",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Set the transponder to \"ON\" (Mode C).",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Set the transponder to \"ALT\" (Mode A).",
    "correctAnswer":"Set the transponder to \"ALT\" (Mode C).",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Set the transponder to \"ON\" (Mode A)."
  },
  { 
    "id":"9a93d3f7-2345-43b1-834d-7410fa6cc7b5",
    "question": "What language must be used to make a radio call?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"French",
    "correctAnswer":"English",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(a)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-07 21:06:58.558330",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"The language of the country the aircraft is operated in",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"The language of the country of aircraft manufacture"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c28bc7c6-e072-4b53-8434-8f8d605f4306",
    "question": "The angular difference between the planned track and the track made good is known as the;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-6",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Closing Angle (CA)",
    "correctAnswer":"Track Error (TE)",
    "syllabusReference":"6.14.2(n)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 18:55:54.833093",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Fix (also known as Position Fix)",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Heading correction"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9ec1f1b5-f131-4bd0-84d1-60e0a8615b95",
    "question": "On an aircraft mounted weather radar, which detects areas of moisture and thus typically thunderstorm activity, the areas of worst turbulence are coloured;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"yellow",
    "correctAnswer":"red",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:18:52.811001",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"green",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"black"
  },
  { 
    "id":"cf7e9bc9-60ad-4481-a887-9b0d4785e6ac",
    "question": " 'Day' is defined as;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"the end of morning civil twilight and the end of evening civil twilight",
    "correctAnswer":"the beginning of morning civil twilight and the end of evening civil twilight",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:00:39.294542",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the beginning of morning civil twilight and the beginning of evening civil twilight",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the end of morning civil twilight and the beginning of evening civil twilight"
  },
  { 
    "id":"9bbd8f4d-7a51-4450-8bc1-1337f179df25",
    "question": "What does the term \"listening watch\" mean?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Identifying traffic both through visual and audio methods.",
    "correctAnswer":"Tuning the designated frequency and staying alert for any mention of your callsign.",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.2(l)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 09:39:12.571602",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"A special type of watch used to improve audio perception.",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Always tuning the emergency frequency 121.5MHz."
  },
  { 
    "id":"95dd3464-9990-4699-b7cd-42d7b41782f9",
    "question": "While flying, over the aviation radio you hear about the crash of an aircraft and the name of the pilot is discussed. Which statement is correct?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"You may not divulge the pilot's name if no other sources are able to verify the information",
    "correctAnswer":"You may not divulge the pilot's name to anyone",
    "syllabusReference":"2.12.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:36:54.405953",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"You may divulge the pilot's name if they are uninjured",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"You may divulge the pilot's name to their relatives"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e241baa2-07f4-44f6-b22b-925b846e6da2",
    "question": "What does a series of red flashes mean when on the ground at an aerodrome?",
    "authorName":"kp","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Stop",
    "correctAnswer":"Taxi clear of landing area in use",
    "syllabusReference":"2.10.4(b)",
    "addedDate":"2023-01-27 20:51:58.968133",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Danger, be on the alert",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Return to starting point on aerodrome"
  },
  { 
    "id":"c7022215-f26d-4f16-bd27-12b32c2f0dbe",
    "question": "You take off from an airfield which is 165 feet AMSL with the correct QNH of 1008 set. Upon landing at your destination, which is 45 feet AMSL, your altimeter reads 315 feet AMSL. Assuming a standard pressure change of 1 hPa per 30 feet, what is the correct QNH at your destination aerodrome?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"1017 hPa",
    "correctAnswer":"999 hPa",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:30:44.126742",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"998 hPa",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"1018 hPa"
  },
  { 
    "id":"863c3a54-1c99-403e-ba9c-eaec7f101347",
    "question": "  A 'Series type B' NOTAM is used predominantly for;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"significant events, such as volcanic eruptions",
    "correctAnswer":"international operations",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 01:38:47.968074",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"domestic operations",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"VFR operations"
  },
  { 
    "id":"3b7c55aa-41c2-4c18-a568-1f74dd6114f6",
    "question": " The minimum fuel reserve for a VFR flight by night in an aeroplane is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"60 minutes",
    "correctAnswer":"45 minutes",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:02:35.304732",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"30 minutes",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"15 minutes"
  },
  { 
    "id":"304086e4-e186-428a-a2ce-87194ce6719e",
    "question": "After a warm front has passed over an area, what conditions should you expect?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"The wind will back with a large increase in strength",
    "correctAnswer":"Possibly some low level cloud but no high level cloud",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 03:24:05.294273",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"A sharp decline in temperature from that before the front",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Relative humidity and dew point will decrease"
  },
  { 
    "id":"1e9947df-6bdb-4ac5-b645-94882c4793a5",
    "question": " Cols are associated with;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-5",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"occluded fronts only",
    "correctAnswer":"extensive areas of fog during winter",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 10:33:36.148079",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"high pressure only",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"strong winds in winter and summer months"
  },
  { 
    "id":"86ed178e-4643-40d1-b0cb-55f6e6345480",
    "question": "In order to keep a PPL current, a Biennial Flight Review (BFR) must have been completed;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"within the last year, if a ZFT simulator is used for demonstrating competency",
    "correctAnswer":"within the last two years, though it can be conducted up to a maximum of 60 days prior to the due date",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-12 09:54:20.706211",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"within the last two years, though it can be conducted up to a maximum of 30 days prior to the due date",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"within one year of obtaining a class 1 or class 2 medical certificate"
  },
  { 
    "id":"e09757a8-5f45-49f8-9277-732beffc16e5",
    "question": " The weather typically associated with an INACTIVE Intertropical Convergence Zone (ITCZ) is;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"developments of cirrostratus and altocirrus cloud",
    "correctAnswer":"some shower activity and developments of cirrus cloud",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 10:09:09.744979",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"moderate to severe icing",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"large developments of cumulonimbus cloud"
  },
  { 
    "id":"50947832-5724-4780-9e99-2b710b2b3fab",
    "question": "You have previously made a PAN PAN call but now wish to cancel that call. What words must your transmission to cancel the call include?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"ppl-3",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"PAN PAN resolved",
    "correctAnswer":"Cancel PAN PAN",
    "syllabusReference":"2.14.8",
    "addedDate":"2021-10-09 02:38:10.203304",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Negative PAN PAN",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"All Stations, PAN PAN situation no longer applies"
  },
  { 
    "id":"45e30b25-fe50-4a47-989f-f4179da77364",
    "question": "A 'clearance limit' means;",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-1",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"a defined rectangular area on the ground or water at the departure end of the runway",
    "correctAnswer":"the point to which an aircraft is granted an ATC clearance",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-13 09:32:07.467889",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"the point, measured in feet AMSL, which an aircraft must reach prior to initiating a turn",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"the point, measured in feet AGL, above which an aircraft must pass over an obstacle"
  },
  { 
    "id":"89d464c0-cc29-4a4e-be72-58755081d78f",
    "question": "Prior to a warm front arriving at a location, what conditions can be expected?",
    "authorName":"","examId":"cpl-4",
    "incorrectAnswer1":"Dew point will decrease and temperature will increase",
    "correctAnswer":"Pressure will decrease and wind will veer and increase in strength",
    "syllabusReference":"",
    "addedDate":"2021-09-19 02:49:16.702180",
    "incorrectAnswer2":"Visibility will become good, with no cloud in the immediate vicinity",
    "incorrectAnswer3":"Relative humidity will decrease and thunderstorms will form"
  }
]